[{"questionId":"A-001-001-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The time required for the current in thecircuit to build up to 63.2% of themaximum value"},{"letter":"B","text":"The time required for the current in thecircuit to build up to 36.8% of themaximum value"},{"letter":"C","text":"The time required for the voltage in thecircuit to build up to 63.2% of themaximum value"},{"letter":"D","text":"The time required for the voltage in thecircuit to build up to 36.8% of themaximum value"}],"questionText":"What is the meaning of the term \"timeconstant\" in an RL circuit?"},{"questionId":"A-001-001-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"One time constant"},{"letter":"B","text":"An exponential rate of one"},{"letter":"C","text":"A time factor of one"},{"letter":"D","text":"One exponential period"}],"questionText":"What is the term for the time required for thecapacitor in an RC circuit to be charged to63.2% of the supply voltage?"},{"questionId":"A-001-001-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"One exponential rate"},{"letter":"B","text":"One time constant"},{"letter":"C","text":"An exponential period of one"},{"letter":"D","text":"A time factor of one"}],"questionText":"What is the term for the time required for thecurrent in an RL circuit to build up to 63.2%of the maximum value?"},{"questionId":"A-001-001-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"One time constant"},{"letter":"B","text":"A discharge factor of one"},{"letter":"C","text":"An exponential discharge of one"},{"letter":"D","text":"One discharge period"}],"questionText":"What is the term for the time it takes for acharged capacitor in an RC circuit todischarge to 36.8% of its initial value ofstored charge?"},{"questionId":"A-001-001-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A voltage that opposes the applied EMF"},{"letter":"B","text":"A current that opposes the applied EMF"},{"letter":"C","text":"An opposing EMF equal to R times Cpercent of the applied EMF"},{"letter":"D","text":"A current equal to the applied EMF"}],"questionText":"What is meant by \"back EMF\"?"},{"questionId":"A-001-001-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"36.8%"},{"letter":"B","text":"86.5%"},{"letter":"C","text":"63.2%"},{"letter":"D","text":"95%"}],"questionText":"After two time constants, the capacitor in anRC circuit is charged to what percentage ofthe supply voltage?"},{"questionId":"A-001-001-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"86.5%"},{"letter":"B","text":"63.2%"},{"letter":"C","text":"13.5%"},{"letter":"D","text":"36.8%"}],"questionText":"After two time constants, the capacitor in anRC circuit is discharged to what percentageof the starting voltage?"},{"questionId":"A-001-001-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"4700 seconds"},{"letter":"B","text":"470 seconds"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.47 seconds"},{"letter":"D","text":"47 seconds"}],"questionText":"What is the time constant of a circuit havinga 100 microfarad capacitor in series with a470 kilohm resistor?"},{"questionId":"A-001-001-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"470 seconds"},{"letter":"B","text":"220 seconds"},{"letter":"C","text":"103 seconds"},{"letter":"D","text":"470 000 seconds"}],"questionText":"What is the time constant of a circuit havinga 220 microfarad capacitor in series with a470 kilohm resistor?"},{"questionId":"A-001-002-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Thermal effects on the surface of theconductor increase impedance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Thermal effects on the surface of theconductor decrease impedance"},{"letter":"C","text":"As frequency increases, RF current flowsin a thinner layer of the conductor, closerto the surface"},{"letter":"D","text":"As frequency decreases, RF currentflows in a thinner layer of the conductor,closer to the surface"}],"questionText":"What is the result of skin effect?"},{"questionId":"A-001-002-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Skin effect"},{"letter":"B","text":"Piezoelectric effect"},{"letter":"C","text":"Resonance effect"},{"letter":"D","text":"Layer effect"}],"questionText":"What effect causes most of an RF current toflow along the surface of a conductor?"},{"questionId":"A-001-002-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"In a magnetic field in the centre of theconductor"},{"letter":"B","text":"In a magnetic field around the conductor"},{"letter":"C","text":"In the centre of the conductor"},{"letter":"D","text":"Along the surface of the conductor"}],"questionText":"Where does almost all RF current flow in aconductor?"},{"questionId":"A-001-002-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Because of heating of the conductor'sinterior"},{"letter":"B","text":"Because of skin effect"},{"letter":"C","text":"Because the RF resistance of aconductor is much less than the DCresistance"},{"letter":"D","text":"Because a conductor has AC resistancedue to self-inductance"}],"questionText":"Why does most of an RF current flow withina very thin layer under the conductor'ssurface?"},{"questionId":"A-001-002-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Because of the Hertzberg effect"},{"letter":"B","text":"Because conductors are non-lineardevices"},{"letter":"C","text":"Because the insulation conducts currentat high frequencies"},{"letter":"D","text":"Because of skin effect"}],"questionText":"Why is the resistance of a conductordifferent for RF currents than for directcurrents?"},{"questionId":"A-001-002-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Watt"},{"letter":"B","text":"Volt"},{"letter":"C","text":"Farad"},{"letter":"D","text":"Coulomb"}],"questionText":"What unit measures the ability of acapacitor to store electrical charge?"},{"questionId":"A-001-002-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a cloud of electrons"},{"letter":"B","text":"a skin effect that diminishes withdistance"},{"letter":"C","text":"an electromagnetic field"},{"letter":"D","text":"an electrostatic field"}],"questionText":"A wire has a current passing through it.Surrounding this wire there is:"},{"questionId":"A-001-002-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Kinetic energy"},{"letter":"B","text":"Ampere-joules"},{"letter":"C","text":"Joule-coulombs"},{"letter":"D","text":"Potential energy"}],"questionText":"What is the term for energy that is stored inan electromagnetic or electrostatic field?"},{"questionId":"A-001-002-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"an electric current"},{"letter":"B","text":"an electrostatic field"},{"letter":"C","text":"a magnetic field"},{"letter":"D","text":"a cloud of electrons"}],"questionText":"Between the charged plates of a capacitorthere is:"},{"questionId":"A-001-002-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"coulomb"},{"letter":"B","text":"farad"},{"letter":"C","text":"watt"},{"letter":"D","text":"henry"}],"questionText":"Energy is stored within an inductor that iscarrying a current. The amount of energydepends on this current, but it also dependson a property of the inductor. This propertyhas the following unit:"},{"questionId":"A-001-003-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"79.6 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"3.56 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"1.78 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"7.96 MHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a seriesRLC circuit if R is 47 ohms, L is 50microhenrys and C is 40 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-003-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1.78 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"1.78 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"1.99 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"1.99 MHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a seriesRLC circuit, if R is 47 ohms, L is 40microhenrys and C is 200 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-003-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"7.12 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"3.18 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"3.18 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"7.12 MHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a seriesRLC circuit, if R is 47 ohms, L is 50microhenrys and C is 10 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-003-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"10.1 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"63.7 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"10.1 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"63.7 MHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a seriesRLC circuit, if R is 47 ohms, L is 25microhenrys and C is 10 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-003-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"14.5 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"13.1 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"13.1 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"14.5 kHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a seriesRLC circuit, if R is 47 ohms, L is 3microhenrys and C is 40 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-003-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"17.8 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"17.8 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"19.9 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"19.9 kHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a seriesRLC circuit, if R is 47 ohms, L is 4microhenrys and C is 20 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-003-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"35.4 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"23.7 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"23.7 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"35.4 MHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a seriesRLC circuit, if R is 47 ohms, L is 3microhenrys and C is 15 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-003-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"49.7 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"28.1 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"28.1 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"49.7 MHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a seriesRLC circuit, if R is 47 ohms, L is 4microhenrys and C is 8 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-003-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"5.31 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"17.7 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"1.77 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"53.1 MHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a seriesRLC circuit, if R is 47 ohms, L is 1microhenry and C is 9 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-003-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2.2 picofarads"},{"letter":"B","text":"44 picofarads"},{"letter":"C","text":"2.2 microfarads"},{"letter":"D","text":"44 microfarads"}],"questionText":"What is the value of capacitance (C) in aseries R-L-C circuit, if the circuit resonantfrequency is 14.25 MHz and L is 2.84microhenrys?"},{"questionId":"A-001-004-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"15.9 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"50.3 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"15.9 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"50.3 kHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a parallelRLC circuit if R is 4.7 kilohms, L is 1microhenry and C is 10 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-004-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"5.31 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"5.31 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"29.1 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"29.1 kHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a parallelRLC circuit if R is 4.7 kilohms, L is 2microhenrys and C is 15 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-004-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3.54 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"3.54 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"23.7 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"23.7 kHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a parallelRLC circuit if R is 4.7 kilohms, L is 5microhenrys and C is 9 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-004-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"20.5 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"2.65 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"2.65 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"20.5 kHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a parallelRLC circuit if R is 4.7 kilohms, L is 2microhenrys and C is 30 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-004-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"18.4 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"2.12 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"2.12 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"18.4 kHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a parallelRLC circuit if R is 4.7 kilohms, L is 15microhenrys and C is 5 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-004-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"10.3 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"10.3 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"6.63 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"6.63 kHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a parallelRLC circuit if R is 4.7 kilohms, L is 40microhenrys and C is 6 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-004-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"7.12 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"7.12 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"3.18 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"3.18 kHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a parallelRLC circuit if R is 4.7 kilohms, L is 10microhenrys and C is 50 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-004-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3.56 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"7.96 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"7.96 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"3.56 MHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a parallelRLC circuit if R is 4.7 kilohms, L is 200microhenrys and C is 10 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-004-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1.68 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"1.68 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"1.77 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"1.77 MHz"}],"questionText":"What is the resonant frequency of a parallelRLC circuit if R is 4.7 kilohms, L is 90microhenrys and C is 100 picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-004-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3.9 millihenrys"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.353 microhenry"},{"letter":"C","text":"2.8 microhenrys"},{"letter":"D","text":"253.8 millihenrys"}],"questionText":"What is the value of inductance (L) in aparallel RLC circuit, if the resonantfrequency is 14.25 MHz and C is 44picofarads?"},{"questionId":"A-001-005-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"75.1"},{"letter":"B","text":"7.51"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.013"},{"letter":"D","text":"71.5"}],"questionText":"What is the Q of a parallel RLC circuit, if it isresonant at 14.128 MHz, L is 2.7microhenrys and R is 18 kilohms?"},{"questionId":"A-001-005-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"43.1"},{"letter":"B","text":"13.3"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.023"},{"letter":"D","text":"4.31"}],"questionText":"What is the Q of a parallel RLC circuit, if it isresonant at 14.128 MHz, L is 4.7microhenrys and R is 18 kilohms?"},{"questionId":"A-001-005-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"7.35"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.00735"},{"letter":"C","text":"13.3"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.136"}],"questionText":"What is the Q of a parallel RLC circuit, if it isresonant at 4.468 MHz, L is 47 microhenrysand R is 180 ohms?"},{"questionId":"A-001-005-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"31.9"},{"letter":"B","text":"7.35"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.0319"},{"letter":"D","text":"71.5"}],"questionText":"What is the Q of a parallel RLC circuit, if it isresonant at 14.225 MHz, L is 3.5microhenrys and R is 10 kilohms?"},{"questionId":"A-001-005-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"0.00452"},{"letter":"B","text":"4.52"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.221"},{"letter":"D","text":"22.1"}],"questionText":"What is the Q of a parallel RLC circuit, if it isresonant at 7.125 MHz, L is 10.1microhenrys and R is 100 ohms?"},{"questionId":"A-001-005-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"25.6"},{"letter":"B","text":"39"},{"letter":"C","text":"22.1"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.0256"}],"questionText":"What is the Q of a parallel RLC circuit, if it isresonant at 7.125 MHz, L is 12.6microhenrys and R is 22 kilohms?"},{"questionId":"A-001-005-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"31.1"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.031"},{"letter":"C","text":"32.2"},{"letter":"D","text":"25.6"}],"questionText":"What is the Q of a parallel RLC circuit, if it isresonant at 3.625 MHz, L is 3 microhenrysand R is 2.2 kilohms?"},{"questionId":"A-001-005-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"4.35"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.00435"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.23"},{"letter":"D","text":"2.3"}],"questionText":"What is the Q of a parallel RLC circuit, if it isresonant at 3.625 MHz, L is 42 microhenrysand R is 220 ohms?"},{"questionId":"A-001-005-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"54.3"},{"letter":"B","text":"23"},{"letter":"C","text":"1.84"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.543"}],"questionText":"What is the Q of a parallel RLC circuit, if it isresonant at 3.625 MHz, L is 43 microhenrysand R is 1.8 kilohms?"},{"questionId":"A-001-005-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To increase the Q and decrease the skineffect"},{"letter":"B","text":"To decrease the Q and increase theresonant frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"To increase the Q and decreasebandwidth"},{"letter":"D","text":"To decrease the Q and increase thebandwidth"}],"questionText":"Why is a resistor often included in a parallelresonant circuit?"},{"questionId":"A-002-001-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Silicon and germanium"},{"letter":"B","text":"Galena and germanium"},{"letter":"C","text":"Galena and bismuth"},{"letter":"D","text":"Silicon and gold"}],"questionText":"What two elements widely used insemiconductor devices exhibit both metallicand non-metallic characteristics?"},{"questionId":"A-002-001-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"In bipolar transistors"},{"letter":"B","text":"At microwave frequencies"},{"letter":"C","text":"In high-power circuits"},{"letter":"D","text":"At very low frequencies"}],"questionText":"In what application is gallium-arsenide usedas a semiconductor material in preference togermanium or silicon?"},{"questionId":"A-002-001-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"P-type"},{"letter":"B","text":"N-type"},{"letter":"C","text":"Bipolar type"},{"letter":"D","text":"Superconductor type"}],"questionText":"What type of semiconductor materialcontains fewer free electrons than puregermanium or silicon crystals?"},{"questionId":"A-002-001-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Free protons"},{"letter":"B","text":"Free neutrons"},{"letter":"C","text":"Holes"},{"letter":"D","text":"Free electrons"}],"questionText":"What are the majority charge carriers in P-type semiconductor material?"},{"questionId":"A-002-001-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Free electrons"},{"letter":"B","text":"Holes"},{"letter":"C","text":"Free protons"},{"letter":"D","text":"Free neutrons"}],"questionText":"What are the majority charge carriers in N-type semiconductor material?"},{"questionId":"A-002-001-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a semiconductor"},{"letter":"B","text":"a conductor"},{"letter":"C","text":"an insulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"a superconductor"}],"questionText":"Silicon, in its pure form, is:"},{"questionId":"A-002-001-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"intrinsic conductor"},{"letter":"B","text":"N-type conductor"},{"letter":"C","text":"P-type conductor"},{"letter":"D","text":"semiconductor"}],"questionText":"An element which is sometimes an insulatorand sometimes a conductor is called a:"},{"questionId":"A-002-001-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Silicon"},{"letter":"B","text":"Tantalum"},{"letter":"C","text":"Copper"},{"letter":"D","text":"Sulphur"}],"questionText":"Which of the following materials is used tomake a semiconductor?"},{"questionId":"A-002-001-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"insulators"},{"letter":"B","text":"conductors"},{"letter":"C","text":"tuned circuits"},{"letter":"D","text":"inductors"}],"questionText":"Substances such as silicon in a pure stateare usually good:"},{"questionId":"A-002-001-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"protons"},{"letter":"B","text":"ions"},{"letter":"C","text":"electrons"},{"letter":"D","text":"impurities"}],"questionText":"A semiconductor is said to be doped when ithas added to it small quantities of:"},{"questionId":"A-002-002-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An internal capacitance that varies withthe applied voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"A constant voltage under conditions ofvarying current"},{"letter":"C","text":"A constant current under conditions ofvarying voltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"A negative resistance region"}],"questionText":"What is the principal characteristic of aZener diode?"},{"questionId":"A-002-002-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Zener"},{"letter":"B","text":"Silicon-controlled rectifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"Hot-carrier (Schottky)"},{"letter":"D","text":"Varactor"}],"questionText":"What type of semiconductor diode varies itsinternal capacitance as the voltage appliedto its terminals varies?"},{"questionId":"A-002-002-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"As a variable capacitance in anautomatic frequency control (AFC) circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"As a constant voltage reference in apower supply"},{"letter":"C","text":"As VHF and UHF mixers and detectors"},{"letter":"D","text":"As balanced mixers in FM generation"}],"questionText":"What is a common use for the hot-carrier(Schottky) diode?"},{"questionId":"A-002-002-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Maximum forward current andcapacitance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Maximum reverse current and peakinverse voltage (PIV)"},{"letter":"C","text":"Maximum forward current and peakinverse voltage (PIV)"},{"letter":"D","text":"Maximum reverse current andcapacitance"}],"questionText":"What are the major ratings for junctiondiodes?"},{"questionId":"A-002-002-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Electrolytic and point contact"},{"letter":"B","text":"Electrolytic and junction"},{"letter":"C","text":"Junction and point contact"},{"letter":"D","text":"Vacuum and point contact"}],"questionText":"Structurally, what are the two maincategories of semiconductor diodes?"},{"questionId":"A-002-002-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"As a high voltage rectifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"As an RF detector"},{"letter":"C","text":"As a constant current source"},{"letter":"D","text":"As a constant voltage source"}],"questionText":"What is a common use for point contactdiodes?"},{"questionId":"A-002-002-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"As a constant current source"},{"letter":"B","text":"As a high voltage rectifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"As a constant voltage source"},{"letter":"D","text":"As an RF switch"}],"questionText":"What is one common use for PIN diodes?"},{"questionId":"A-002-002-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"increase current"},{"letter":"B","text":"regulate voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"dissipate voltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"decrease current"}],"questionText":"A Zener diode is a device used to:"},{"questionId":"A-002-002-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"5"},{"letter":"B","text":"50"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.05"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.5"}],"questionText":"If a Zener diode rated at 10 V and 50 wattswas operated at maximum dissipationrating, it would conduct ____ amperes:"},{"questionId":"A-002-002-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"less"},{"letter":"B","text":"the same"},{"letter":"C","text":"much greater"},{"letter":"D","text":"slightly greater"}],"questionText":"The power-handling capability of most Zenerdiodes is rated at 25 degrees C orapproximately room temperature. If thetemperature is increased, the powerhandling capability is:"},{"questionId":"A-002-003-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The change of collector current withrespect to base current"},{"letter":"B","text":"The change of base current with respectto collector current"},{"letter":"C","text":"The change of collector current withrespect to gate current"},{"letter":"D","text":"The change of collector current withrespect to emitter current"}],"questionText":"What is the alpha of a bipolar transistor?"},{"questionId":"A-002-003-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The change of collector current withrespect to emitter current"},{"letter":"B","text":"The change of base current with respectto gate current"},{"letter":"C","text":"The change of collector current withrespect to base current"},{"letter":"D","text":"The change of base current with respectto emitter current"}],"questionText":"What is the beta of a bipolar transistor?"},{"questionId":"A-002-003-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Forward voltage gain"},{"letter":"B","text":"Reverse current gain"},{"letter":"C","text":"Reverse voltage gain"},{"letter":"D","text":"Forward current gain"}],"questionText":"What is the alpha of a bipolar transistor incommon base configuration?"},{"questionId":"A-002-003-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"delta"},{"letter":"B","text":"alpha"},{"letter":"C","text":"beta"},{"letter":"D","text":"gamma"}],"questionText":"In a bipolar transistor, the change ofcollector current with respect to base currentis called:"},{"questionId":"A-002-003-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Common gate"},{"letter":"B","text":"Common emitter"},{"letter":"C","text":"Common base"},{"letter":"D","text":"Common collector"}],"questionText":"The alpha of a bipolar transistor is specifiedfor what configuration?"},{"questionId":"A-002-003-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Common emitter or common gate"},{"letter":"B","text":"Common base or common collector"},{"letter":"C","text":"Common base or common emitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Common emitter or common collector"}],"questionText":"The beta of a bipolar transistor is specifiedfor what configurations?"},{"questionId":"A-002-003-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An NPN transistor"},{"letter":"B","text":"A PNP transistor"},{"letter":"C","text":"A triode vacuum tube"},{"letter":"D","text":"A varactor"}],"questionText":"Which component conducts electricity froma positive emitter to a negative collectorwhen its base is made negative?"},{"questionId":"A-002-003-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"beta x (1 + beta)"},{"letter":"B","text":"beta x (1 - beta)"},{"letter":"C","text":"beta / (1 - beta)"},{"letter":"D","text":"beta / (1 + beta)"}],"questionText":"Alpha of a bipolar transistor is equal to:"},{"questionId":"A-002-003-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"usually about half"},{"letter":"B","text":"high to very high"},{"letter":"C","text":"very low"},{"letter":"D","text":"usually about double"}],"questionText":"The current gain of a bipolar transistor incommon emitter or common collectorcompared to common base configuration is:"},{"questionId":"A-002-003-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"alpha / (1 + alpha)"},{"letter":"B","text":"alpha x (1 - alpha)"},{"letter":"C","text":"alpha x (1 + alpha)"},{"letter":"D","text":"alpha / (1 - alpha)"}],"questionText":"Beta of a bipolar transistor is equal to:"},{"questionId":"A-002-004-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An FET without a channel; no currentoccurs with zero gate voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"An FET with a channel that blocksvoltage through the gate"},{"letter":"C","text":"An FET with a channel that allowscurrent when the gate voltage is zero"},{"letter":"D","text":"An FET without a channel to hindercurrent through the gate"}],"questionText":"What is an enhancement-mode FET?"},{"questionId":"A-002-004-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The gate-protective Zener diode keepsthe gate voltage within specifications toprevent the device from overheating"},{"letter":"B","text":"The gate-protective Zener diode protectsthe substrate from excessive voltages"},{"letter":"C","text":"The gate-protective Zener diode providesa voltage reference to provide the correctamount of reverse-bias gate voltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"The gate-protective Zener diode preventsthe gate insulation from being puncturedby small static charges or excessivevoltages"}],"questionText":"Why do many MOSFET devices have built-ingate protective Zener diodes?"},{"questionId":"A-002-004-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"They are light-sensitive"},{"letter":"B","text":"They have micro-welded semiconductorjunctions that are susceptible tobreakage"},{"letter":"C","text":"They have fragile leads that may break off"},{"letter":"D","text":"They are susceptible to damage fromstatic charges"}],"questionText":"Why are special precautions necessary inhandling FET and CMOS devices?"},{"questionId":"A-002-004-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The input impedance of FETs and bipolartransistors is the same"},{"letter":"B","text":"An FET has high input impedance; abipolar transistor has low inputimpedance"},{"letter":"C","text":"One cannot compare input impedancewithout knowing supply voltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"An FET has low input impedance; abipolar transistor has high inputimpedance"}],"questionText":"How does the input impedance of a field-effect transistor (FET) compare with that of abipolar transistor?"},{"questionId":"A-002-004-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Gate, drain, source"},{"letter":"B","text":"Emitter, base 1, base 2"},{"letter":"C","text":"Emitter, base, collector"},{"letter":"D","text":"Gate 1, gate 2, drain"}],"questionText":"What are the three terminals of a junctionfield-effect transistor (JFET)?"},{"questionId":"A-002-004-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"High power and low power"},{"letter":"B","text":"MOSFET and GaAsFET"},{"letter":"C","text":"Silicon and germanium"},{"letter":"D","text":"N-channel and P-channel"}],"questionText":"What are the two basic types of junctionfield-effect transistors (JFET)?"},{"questionId":"A-002-004-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"p-channel enhancement"},{"letter":"B","text":"q-channel enhancement"},{"letter":"C","text":"n-channel depletion"},{"letter":"D","text":"p-channel depletion"}],"questionText":"Electron conduction in an n-channeldepletion type MOSFET is associated with:"},{"questionId":"A-002-004-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"q-channel depletion"},{"letter":"B","text":"p-channel enhancement"},{"letter":"C","text":"p-channel depletion"},{"letter":"D","text":"n-channel enhancement"}],"questionText":"Electron conduction in an n-channelenhancement MOSFET is associated with:"},{"questionId":"A-002-004-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"q-channel depletion"},{"letter":"B","text":"n-channel depletion"},{"letter":"C","text":"p-channel depletion"},{"letter":"D","text":"n-channel enhancement"}],"questionText":"Hole conduction in a p-channel depletiontype MOSFET is associated with:"},{"questionId":"A-002-004-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"n-channel enhancement"},{"letter":"B","text":"q-channel depletion"},{"letter":"C","text":"p-channel enhancement"},{"letter":"D","text":"n-channel depletion"}],"questionText":"Hole conduction in a p-channelenhancement type MOSFET is associatedwith:"},{"questionId":"A-002-005-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"NPN conduction and PNP conduction"},{"letter":"B","text":"Oscillating and quiescent"},{"letter":"C","text":"Conducting and non-conducting"},{"letter":"D","text":"Forward conducting and reverseconducting"}],"questionText":"What are the two stable operating conditionsof a silicon controlled rectifier (SCR)?"},{"questionId":"A-002-005-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The PIN diode"},{"letter":"B","text":"The hot-carrier (Schottky) diode"},{"letter":"C","text":"The varactor diode"},{"letter":"D","text":"The junction diode"}],"questionText":"When a silicon controlled rectifier (SCR) istriggered, to what other semiconductor diodeare its electrical characteristics similar (asmeasured between its cathode and anode)?"},{"questionId":"A-002-005-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"During a switching transition"},{"letter":"B","text":"When it is gated \"on\""},{"letter":"C","text":"When it is gated \"off\""},{"letter":"D","text":"When it is used as a detector"}],"questionText":"Under what operating condition does asilicon controlled rectifier (SCR) exhibitelectrical characteristics similar to a forward-biased silicon rectifier?"},{"questionId":"A-002-005-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"PPNN"},{"letter":"B","text":"PNPN"},{"letter":"C","text":"NPPN"},{"letter":"D","text":"PNNP"}],"questionText":"The silicon controlled rectifier (SCR) is whattype of device?"},{"questionId":"A-002-005-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"anode"},{"letter":"B","text":"cathode"},{"letter":"C","text":"emitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"gate"}],"questionText":"The control element in the silicon controlledrectifier (SCR) is called the:"},{"questionId":"A-002-005-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Thyristors"},{"letter":"B","text":"Phase locked loops"},{"letter":"C","text":"Varactors"},{"letter":"D","text":"Varistors"}],"questionText":"The silicon controlled rectifier (SCR) is amember of which family?"},{"questionId":"A-002-005-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Microphone preamplifier circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"SWR detector circuit"},{"letter":"C","text":"Power supply overvoltage \"crowbar\"circuit"},{"letter":"D","text":"Class C amplifier circuit"}],"questionText":"In amateur radio equipment, which is themajor application for the silicon controlledrectifier (SCR)?"},{"questionId":"A-002-005-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The field effect transistor"},{"letter":"B","text":"The triode vacuum tube"},{"letter":"C","text":"The silicon controlled rectifier (SCR)"},{"letter":"D","text":"The bipolar transistor"}],"questionText":"Which of the following devices has anode,cathode, and gate?"},{"questionId":"A-002-005-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"reverse-biased hot-carrier (Schottky)diode"},{"letter":"B","text":"forward-biased silicon rectifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"reverse-biased silicon rectifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"forward-biased PIN diode"}],"questionText":"When it is gated \"on\", the silicon controlledrectifier (SCR) exhibits electricalcharacteristics similar to a:"},{"questionId":"A-002-006-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Less than 180 degrees"},{"letter":"B","text":"The entire cycle"},{"letter":"C","text":"Exactly 180 degrees"},{"letter":"D","text":"More than 180 degrees but less than 360degrees"}],"questionText":"For what portion of a signal cycle does aClass A amplifier operate?"},{"questionId":"A-002-006-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Class B"},{"letter":"B","text":"Class C"},{"letter":"C","text":"Class A"},{"letter":"D","text":"Class AB"}],"questionText":"Which class of amplifier has the highestlinearity and least distortion?"},{"questionId":"A-002-006-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Exactly 180 degrees"},{"letter":"B","text":"The entire cycle"},{"letter":"C","text":"Less than 180 degrees"},{"letter":"D","text":"More than 180 degrees but less than 360degrees"}],"questionText":"For what portion of a cycle does a Class ABamplifier operate?"},{"questionId":"A-002-006-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Less than 180 degrees"},{"letter":"B","text":"More than 180 degrees but less than 360degrees"},{"letter":"C","text":"The entire cycle"},{"letter":"D","text":"180 degrees"}],"questionText":"For what portion of a cycle does a Class Bamplifier operate?"},{"questionId":"A-002-006-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Less than 180 degrees"},{"letter":"B","text":"More than 180 degrees but less than 360degrees"},{"letter":"C","text":"The entire cycle"},{"letter":"D","text":"180 degrees"}],"questionText":"For what portion of a signal cycle does aClass C amplifier operate?"},{"questionId":"A-002-006-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Class B"},{"letter":"B","text":"Class C"},{"letter":"C","text":"Class A"},{"letter":"D","text":"Class AB"}],"questionText":"Which of the following classes of amplifierprovides the highest efficiency?"},{"questionId":"A-002-006-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Class C"},{"letter":"B","text":"Class AB"},{"letter":"C","text":"Class B"},{"letter":"D","text":"Class A"}],"questionText":"Which of the following classes of amplifierwould provide the highest efficiency in theoutput stage of a CW, RTTY or FMtransmitter?"},{"questionId":"A-002-006-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Class A"},{"letter":"B","text":"Class C"},{"letter":"C","text":"Class B"},{"letter":"D","text":"Class AB"}],"questionText":"Which class of amplifier provides the leastefficiency?"},{"questionId":"A-002-006-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Class A"},{"letter":"B","text":"Class B"},{"letter":"C","text":"Class C"},{"letter":"D","text":"Class AB"}],"questionText":"Which class of amplifier has the poorestlinearity and the most distortion?"},{"questionId":"A-002-006-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Class AB"},{"letter":"B","text":"Class A"},{"letter":"C","text":"Class B"},{"letter":"D","text":"Class C"}],"questionText":"Which class of amplifier operates over lessthan 180 degrees of the cycle?"},{"questionId":"A-002-007-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The input impedance is essentiallydetermined by the resistance betweenthe source and substrate"},{"letter":"B","text":"The input impedance is essentiallydetermined by the resistance betweenthe source and the drain"},{"letter":"C","text":"The input impedance is essentiallydetermined by the resistance betweenthe drain and substrate"},{"letter":"D","text":"The input impedance is essentiallydetermined by the gate biasing network"}],"questionText":"What determines the input impedance of aFET common-source amplifier?"},{"questionId":"A-002-007-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The output impedance is essentiallydetermined by the input impedance of theFET"},{"letter":"B","text":"The output impedance is essentiallydetermined by the drain resistor"},{"letter":"C","text":"The output impedance is essentiallydetermined by the drain supply voltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"The output impedance is essentiallydetermined by the gate supply voltage"}],"questionText":"What determines the output impedance of aFET common-source amplifier?"},{"questionId":"A-002-007-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Mutual gain, high stability and low mutualinductance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Mutual gain, low input impedance andlow output impedance"},{"letter":"C","text":"Low output impedance, high mutualimpedance and low output current"},{"letter":"D","text":"High gain, high input impedance and lowoutput impedance"}],"questionText":"What are the advantages of a Darlington pairaudio amplifier?"},{"questionId":"A-002-007-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the output signal lags the input signal by90 degrees"},{"letter":"B","text":"the output signals leads the input signalby 90 degrees"},{"letter":"C","text":"the signals are 180 degrees out of phase"},{"letter":"D","text":"the signals are in phase"}],"questionText":"In the common base amplifier, when theinput and output signals are compared:"},{"questionId":"A-002-007-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"only slightly lower"},{"letter":"B","text":"very high"},{"letter":"C","text":"very low"},{"letter":"D","text":"only slightly higher"}],"questionText":"In the common base amplifier, the inputimpedance, when compared to the outputimpedance is:"},{"questionId":"A-002-007-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the signals are 180 degrees out of phase"},{"letter":"B","text":"the output signal leads the input signalby 90 degrees"},{"letter":"C","text":"the output signal lags the input signal by90 degrees"},{"letter":"D","text":"the signals are in phase"}],"questionText":"In the common emitter amplifier, when theinput and output signals are compared:"},{"questionId":"A-002-007-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the output signal leads the input signalby 90 degrees"},{"letter":"B","text":"the output signal lags the input signal by90 degrees"},{"letter":"C","text":"the signals are 180 degrees out of phase"},{"letter":"D","text":"the signals are in phase"}],"questionText":"In the common collector amplifier, when theinput and output signals are compared:"},{"questionId":"A-002-007-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Common base"},{"letter":"B","text":"Common mode"},{"letter":"C","text":"Common emitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Common collector"}],"questionText":"The FET amplifier common source circuit issimilar to which of the following bipolartransistor amplifier circuits?"},{"questionId":"A-002-007-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Common base"},{"letter":"B","text":"Common mode"},{"letter":"C","text":"Common collector"},{"letter":"D","text":"Common emitter"}],"questionText":"The FET amplifier common drain circuit issimilar to which of the following bipolartransistor amplifier circuits?"},{"questionId":"A-002-007-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Common base"},{"letter":"B","text":"Common mode"},{"letter":"C","text":"Common collector"},{"letter":"D","text":"Common emitter"}],"questionText":"The FET amplifier common gate circuit issimilar to which of the following bipolartransistor amplifier circuits?"},{"questionId":"A-002-008-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A high-gain, direct-coupled differentialamplifier whose characteristics aredetermined by components mountedexternally"},{"letter":"B","text":"A high-gain, direct-coupled audioamplifier whose characteristics aredetermined by internal components of thedevice"},{"letter":"C","text":"An amplifier used to increase the averageoutput of frequency modulated amateursignals to the legal limit"},{"letter":"D","text":"A program subroutine that calculates thegain of an RF amplifier"}],"questionText":"What is an operational amplifier (op-amp)?"},{"questionId":"A-002-008-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Infinite input impedance, zero outputimpedance, infinite gain, and flatfrequency response"},{"letter":"B","text":"Zero input impedance, zero outputimpedance, infinite gain, and flatfrequency response"},{"letter":"C","text":"Infinite input impedance, infinite outputimpedance, infinite gain and flatfrequency response"},{"letter":"D","text":"Zero input impedance, infinite outputimpedance, infinite gain, and flatfrequency response"}],"questionText":"What would be the characteristics of theideal op-amp?"},{"questionId":"A-002-008-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The external feedback network"},{"letter":"B","text":"The PNP collector load"},{"letter":"C","text":"The voltage applied to the circuit"},{"letter":"D","text":"The collector-to-base capacitance of thePNP stage"}],"questionText":"What determines the gain of a closed-loopop-amp circuit?"},{"questionId":"A-002-008-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The potential between the amplifier inputterminals of the op-amp in an open-loopcondition"},{"letter":"B","text":"The output voltage of the op-amp minusits input voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"The potential between the amplifier inputterminals of the op-amp in a closed-loopcondition"},{"letter":"D","text":"The difference between the output voltageof the op-amp and the input voltagerequired for the next stage"}],"questionText":"What is meant by the term op-amp offsetvoltage?"},{"questionId":"A-002-008-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Very low"},{"letter":"B","text":"Very high"},{"letter":"C","text":"Exactly 100 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"Exactly 1000 ohms"}],"questionText":"What is the output impedance of atheoretically ideal op-amp?"},{"questionId":"A-002-008-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Op-amps are more rugged and canwithstand more abuse than can LCelements"},{"letter":"B","text":"Op-amps are available in more styles andtypes than are LC elements"},{"letter":"C","text":"Op-amps are fixed at one frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"Op-amps exhibit gain rather thaninsertion loss"}],"questionText":"What are the advantages of using an op-ampinstead of LC elements in an audio filter?"},{"questionId":"A-002-008-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Op-amp circuits are used as low-passfilters at the output of transmitters"},{"letter":"B","text":"Op-amp circuits are used as filters forsmoothing power supply output"},{"letter":"C","text":"Op-amp circuits are used as high-passfilters to block RFI at the input ofreceivers"},{"letter":"D","text":"Op-amp circuits are used as audio filtersfor receivers"}],"questionText":"What are the principal uses of an op-ampRC active filter in amateur circuitry?"},{"questionId":"A-002-008-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An operational amplifier circuit connectedsuch that the input and output signals arein phase"},{"letter":"B","text":"An operational amplifier circuit connectedsuch that the input and output signals are90 degrees out of phase"},{"letter":"C","text":"An operational amplifier circuit connectedsuch that the input impedance is held tozero, while the output impedance is high"},{"letter":"D","text":"An operational amplifier circuit connectedsuch that the input and output signals are180 degrees out of phase"}],"questionText":"What is an inverting op-amp circuit?"},{"questionId":"A-002-008-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An operational amplifier circuit connectedsuch that the input and output signals are180 degrees out of phase"},{"letter":"B","text":"An operational amplifier circuit connectedsuch that the input and output signals arein phase"},{"letter":"C","text":"An operational amplifier circuit connectedsuch that the input and output signals are90 degrees out of phase"},{"letter":"D","text":"An operational amplifier circuit connectedsuch that the input impedance is heldlow, and the output impedance is high"}],"questionText":"What is a non-inverting op-amp circuit?"},{"questionId":"A-002-008-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"High gain audio amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"Summing amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"Operational amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"Difference amplifier"}],"questionText":"What term is most appropriate for a highgain, direct-coupled differential amplifierwhose characteristics are determined bycomponents mounted externally?"},{"questionId":"A-002-009-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The recovery of intelligence from amodulated signal"},{"letter":"B","text":"The elimination of noise in a widebandreceiver by phase comparison"},{"letter":"C","text":"The combination of two signals toproduce sum and difference frequencies"},{"letter":"D","text":"The elimination of noise in a widebandreceiver by phase differentiation"}],"questionText":"What is the mixing process?"},{"questionId":"A-002-009-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A beat frequency is generated"},{"letter":"B","text":"Mixer blanking occurs"},{"letter":"C","text":"Spurious signals are generated"},{"letter":"D","text":"Automatic limiting occurs"}],"questionText":"What occurs when an excessive amount ofsignal energy reaches the mixer circuit?"},{"questionId":"A-002-009-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"part of the output tank circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"a DC blocking capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"part of the input tuned circuit"},{"letter":"D","text":"a by-pass for the circuit"}],"questionText":"In a frequency multiplier circuit, the inputsignal is coupled to the base of a transistorthrough a capacitor. A radio frequencychoke is connected between the base of thetransistor and ground. The capacitor is:"},{"questionId":"A-002-009-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"class B"},{"letter":"B","text":"class A"},{"letter":"C","text":"class C"},{"letter":"D","text":"class AB"}],"questionText":"A frequency multiplier circuit must beoperated in:"},{"questionId":"A-002-009-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"tune L1 to the frequency applied to thebase"},{"letter":"B","text":"provide positive feedback"},{"letter":"C","text":"tune L1 to the desired harmonic"},{"letter":"D","text":"by-pass RF"}],"questionText":"In a frequency multiplier circuit, aninductance (L1) and a variable capacitor (C2)are connected in series between VCC+ andground. The collector of a transistor isconnected to a tap on L1. The purpose ofthe variable capacitor is to:"},{"questionId":"A-002-009-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"form a pi filter with L1 and C2"},{"letter":"B","text":"resonate with L1"},{"letter":"C","text":"by-pass any audio components"},{"letter":"D","text":"provide an RF ground at the VCCconnection point of L1"}],"questionText":"In a frequency multiplier circuit, aninductance (L1) and a variable capacitor (C2)are connected in series between VCC+ andground. The collector of a transistor isconnected to a tap on L1. A fixed capacitor(C3) is connected between the VCC+ side ofL1 and ground. The purpose of C3 is to:"},{"questionId":"A-002-009-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"frequency multiplier"},{"letter":"B","text":"frequency divider"},{"letter":"C","text":"voltage divider"},{"letter":"D","text":"voltage doubler"}],"questionText":"In a frequency multiplier circuit, aninductance (L1) and a variable capacitor (C2)are connected in series between VCC+ andground. The collector of a transistor isconnected to a tap on L1. C2 in conjunctionwith L1 operate as a:"},{"questionId":"A-002-009-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a frequency divider"},{"letter":"B","text":"a frequency multiplier"},{"letter":"C","text":"a VHF/UHF amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"a linear amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a circuit where the components are tunedto resonate at a higher frequency thanapplied, the circuit is most likely a:"},{"questionId":"A-002-009-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A frequency multiplier"},{"letter":"B","text":"A beat frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"A mixer"},{"letter":"D","text":"A linear translator"}],"questionText":"What stage in a transmitter would change a5.3-MHz input signal to 14.3 MHz?"},{"questionId":"A-002-010-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"0\" at itsoutput only when all inputs are logic \"1\""},{"letter":"B","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"1\" at itsoutput only when all inputs are logic \"1\""},{"letter":"C","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"0\" at itsoutput if some but not all of its inputs arelogic \"1\""},{"letter":"D","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"0\" at itsoutput only when all inputs are logic \"0\""}],"questionText":"What is a NAND gate?"},{"questionId":"A-002-010-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"0\" at itsoutput if any input is logic \"1\""},{"letter":"B","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"1\" at itsoutput if any input is logic \"1\""},{"letter":"C","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"0\" at itsoutput if all inputs are logic \"1\""},{"letter":"D","text":"A circuit that produces logic \"1\" at itsoutput if all inputs are logic \"0\""}],"questionText":"What is an OR gate?"},{"questionId":"A-002-010-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"0\" at itsoutput if any or all inputs are logic \"1\""},{"letter":"B","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"0\" at itsoutput only if all inputs are logic \"0\""},{"letter":"C","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"1\" at itsoutput only if all inputs are logic \"1\""},{"letter":"D","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"1\" at itsoutput if some but not all of its inputs arelogic \"1\""}],"questionText":"What is a NOR gate?"},{"questionId":"A-002-010-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"0\" at itsoutput when the input is logic \"1\""},{"letter":"B","text":"A circuit that does not allow datatransmission when its input is high"},{"letter":"C","text":"A circuit that allows data transmissiononly when its input is high"},{"letter":"D","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"1\" at itsoutput when the input is logic \"1\""}],"questionText":"What is a NOT gate (also known as anINVERTER)?"},{"questionId":"A-002-010-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"1\" at itsoutput when all of the inputs are logic \"1\""},{"letter":"B","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"1\" at itsoutput when all of the inputs are logic \"0\""},{"letter":"C","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"1\" at itsoutput when only one of the inputs islogic \"1\""},{"letter":"D","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"0\" at itsoutput when only one of the inputs islogic \"1\""}],"questionText":"What is an EXCLUSIVE OR gate?"},{"questionId":"A-002-010-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"1\" at itsoutput when only one of the inputs arelogic \"1\""},{"letter":"B","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"0\" at itsoutput when all of the inputs are logic \"1\""},{"letter":"C","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"1\" at itsoutput when all of the inputs are logic \"1\""},{"letter":"D","text":"A circuit that produces a logic \"1\" at itsoutput when only one of the inputs islogic \"0\""}],"questionText":"What is an EXCLUSIVE NOR gate?"},{"questionId":"A-002-010-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A binary sequential logic element withtwo stable states"},{"letter":"B","text":"A binary sequential logic element witheight stable states"},{"letter":"C","text":"A binary sequential logic element withfour stable states"},{"letter":"D","text":"A binary sequential logic element withone stable state"}],"questionText":"What is a flip-flop circuit?"},{"questionId":"A-002-010-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A clock"},{"letter":"B","text":"A flip-flop"},{"letter":"C","text":"An OR gate"},{"letter":"D","text":"An AND gate"}],"questionText":"What is a bistable multivibrator?"},{"questionId":"A-002-010-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A flip-flop"},{"letter":"B","text":"A decade counter"},{"letter":"C","text":"An OR gate"},{"letter":"D","text":"An op-amp"}],"questionText":"What type of digital logic is also known as alatch?"},{"questionId":"A-002-010-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"saturated"},{"letter":"B","text":"reverse-biased"},{"letter":"C","text":"forward-biased"},{"letter":"D","text":"cut off"}],"questionText":"In a multivibrator circuit, when one transistorconducts, the other is:"},{"questionId":"A-002-011-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A power supply filter made with interlacedquartz crystals"},{"letter":"B","text":"A filter with narrow bandwidth and steepskirts made using quartz crystals"},{"letter":"C","text":"A filter with wide bandwidth and shallowskirts made using quartz crystals"},{"letter":"D","text":"An audio filter made with four quartzcrystals that resonate at 1 kHz intervals"}],"questionText":"What is a crystal lattice filter?"},{"questionId":"A-002-011-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The relative frequencies of the individualcrystals"},{"letter":"B","text":"The centre frequency chosen for the filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"The gain of the RF stage following thefilter"},{"letter":"D","text":"The amplitude of the signals passingthrough the filter"}],"questionText":"What factor determines the bandwidth andresponse shape of a crystal lattice filter?"},{"questionId":"A-002-011-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2.4 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"15 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"500 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"6 kHz"}],"questionText":"For single-sideband phone emissions, whatwould be the bandwidth of a good crystallattice filter?"},{"questionId":"A-002-011-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"freedom from harmonic emissions"},{"letter":"B","text":"simplicity"},{"letter":"C","text":"much greater frequency stability"},{"letter":"D","text":"longer life under severe operating use"}],"questionText":"The main advantage of a crystal oscillatorover a tuned LC oscillator is:"},{"questionId":"A-002-011-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"LC circuit's high Q"},{"letter":"B","text":"crystal's simplicity"},{"letter":"C","text":"crystal's high Q"},{"letter":"D","text":"crystal's low Q"}],"questionText":"A quartz crystal filter is superior to an LCfilter for narrow bandpass applicationsbecause of the:"},{"questionId":"A-002-011-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A very high Q tuned circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"A very low Q tuned circuit"},{"letter":"C","text":"A variable capacitance"},{"letter":"D","text":"A variable tuned circuit"}],"questionText":"Electrically, what does a crystal look like?"},{"questionId":"A-002-011-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"an overtone oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"a crystal multiplier"},{"letter":"C","text":"a crystal lattice"},{"letter":"D","text":"a crystal ladder"}],"questionText":"Crystals are sometimes used in a circuitwhich has an output close to an integralmultiple of the crystal frequency. This circuitis called:"},{"questionId":"A-002-011-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"High power output"},{"letter":"B","text":"Good frequency stability"},{"letter":"C","text":"Very low noise because of high Q"},{"letter":"D","text":"Good frequency accuracy"}],"questionText":"Which of the following properties does notapply to a crystal when used in an oscillatorcircuit?"},{"questionId":"A-002-011-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Overtone effect"},{"letter":"B","text":"Piezoelectric effect"},{"letter":"C","text":"Hertzberg effect"},{"letter":"D","text":"Ferro-resonance"}],"questionText":"Crystal oscillators, filters and microphonesdepend upon which principle?"},{"questionId":"A-002-011-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Active filters"},{"letter":"B","text":"Microphones"},{"letter":"C","text":"Lattice filters"},{"letter":"D","text":"Oscillators"}],"questionText":"Crystals are not applicable to which of thefollowing?"},{"questionId":"A-002-012-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"High-pass, low-pass and band-pass"},{"letter":"B","text":"Hartley, Colpitts and Pierce"},{"letter":"C","text":"Audio, radio and capacitive"},{"letter":"D","text":"Inductive, capacitive and resistive"}],"questionText":"What are the three general groupings offilters?"},{"questionId":"A-002-012-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It has a maximally flat response over itspass-band"},{"letter":"B","text":"The product of its series and shunt-element impedances is a constant for allfrequencies"},{"letter":"C","text":"It only requires conductors"},{"letter":"D","text":"It only requires capacitors"}],"questionText":"What are the distinguishing features of aButterworth filter?"},{"questionId":"A-002-012-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A Butterworth filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"A Chebyshev filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"An active LC filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"A passive op-amp filter"}],"questionText":"Which filter type is described as havingripple in the passband and a sharp cutoff?"},{"questionId":"A-002-012-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It has a maximally flat response in thepassband"},{"letter":"B","text":"It allows ripple in the passband in returnfor steeper skirts"},{"letter":"C","text":"It requires only inductors"},{"letter":"D","text":"It requires only capacitors"}],"questionText":"What are the distinguishing features of aChebyshev filter?"},{"questionId":"A-002-012-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3.7 metres (12 ft)"},{"letter":"B","text":"1.5 metres (5 ft)"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.6 metres (2 ft)"},{"letter":"D","text":"2.4 metres (8 ft)"}],"questionText":"On VHF and above, 1/4 wavelength coaxialcavities are used to give protection fromhigh-level signals. For a frequency ofapproximately 50 MHz, the diameter of sucha device would be about 10 cm (4 in). Whatwould be its approximate length?"},{"questionId":"A-002-012-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"duplexer"},{"letter":"B","text":"helical resonator"},{"letter":"C","text":"diplexer"},{"letter":"D","text":"directional coupler"}],"questionText":"A device which helps with receiver overloadand spurious responses at VHF, UHF andabove may be installed in the receiver frontend. It is called a:"},{"questionId":"A-002-012-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Butterworth"},{"letter":"B","text":"Chebyshev"},{"letter":"C","text":"none of the other answers"},{"letter":"D","text":"resonant cavity"}],"questionText":"Where you require bandwidth at VHF andhigher frequencies about equal to atelevision channel, a good choice of filter isthe:"},{"questionId":"A-002-012-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It requires only capacitors"},{"letter":"B","text":"It has maximally flat response over itspassband"},{"letter":"C","text":"It allows ripple in the passband in returnfor steeper skirts"},{"letter":"D","text":"It requires only inductors"}],"questionText":"What is the primary advantage of theButterworth filter over the Chebyshev filter?"},{"questionId":"A-002-012-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It requires only capacitors"},{"letter":"B","text":"It requires only inductors"},{"letter":"C","text":"It has maximally flat response over thepassband"},{"letter":"D","text":"It allows ripple in the passband in returnfor steeper skirts"}],"questionText":"What is the primary advantage of theChebyshev filter over the Butterworth filter?"},{"questionId":"A-002-012-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Butterworth"},{"letter":"B","text":"Cavity"},{"letter":"C","text":"Elliptical"},{"letter":"D","text":"Chebyshev"}],"questionText":"Which of the following filter types is notsuitable for use at audio and low radiofrequencies?"},{"questionId":"A-003-001-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Average voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"Peak-to-peak voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"Peak voltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"RMS voltage"}],"questionText":"What is the easiest amplitude dimension tomeasure by viewing a pure sine wave on anoscilloscope?"},{"questionId":"A-003-001-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"300 volts"},{"letter":"B","text":"120 volts"},{"letter":"C","text":"170 volts"},{"letter":"D","text":"240 volts"}],"questionText":"What is the RMS value of a 340 volt peak-to-peak pure sine wave?"},{"questionId":"A-003-001-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The AC voltage found by taking thesquare root of the peak AC voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"The DC voltage causing the same heatingof a given resistor as the peak AC voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"The AC voltage found by taking thesquare root of the average AC value"},{"letter":"D","text":"The AC voltage causing the same heatingof a given resistor as a DC voltage of thesame value"}],"questionText":"What is the equivalent to the RMS value ofan AC voltage?"},{"questionId":"A-003-001-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"average values"},{"letter":"B","text":"average values times 1.414"},{"letter":"C","text":"none of the proposed answers"},{"letter":"D","text":"peak values times 0.707"}],"questionText":"In applying Ohm's law to AC circuits, currentand voltage values are:"},{"questionId":"A-003-001-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"100% of the maximum value"},{"letter":"B","text":"63.6% of the maximum value"},{"letter":"C","text":"70.7% of the maximum value"},{"letter":"D","text":"50% of the maximum value"}],"questionText":"The effective value of a sine wave of voltageor current is:"},{"questionId":"A-003-001-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"peak voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"instantaneous voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"average voltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"RMS voltage"}],"questionText":"AC voltmeter scales are usually calibrated toread:"},{"questionId":"A-003-001-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"peak value"},{"letter":"B","text":"effective value"},{"letter":"C","text":"peak-to-peak value"},{"letter":"D","text":"average value"}],"questionText":"An AC voltmeter is calibrated to read the:"},{"questionId":"A-003-001-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The peak-to-peak value"},{"letter":"B","text":"The RMS value"},{"letter":"C","text":"The average value"},{"letter":"D","text":"The peak value"}],"questionText":"Which AC voltage value will produce thesame amount of heat as a DC voltage, whenapplied to the same resistance?"},{"questionId":"A-003-001-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"204.8 volts"},{"letter":"B","text":"339.5 volts"},{"letter":"C","text":"84.8 volts"},{"letter":"D","text":"169.7 volts"}],"questionText":"What is the peak-to-peak voltage of a sinewave that has an RMS voltage of 120 volts?"},{"questionId":"A-003-001-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"24 volts"},{"letter":"B","text":"34 volts"},{"letter":"C","text":"8.5 volts"},{"letter":"D","text":"12 volts"}],"questionText":"A sine wave of 17 volts peak is equivalent tohow many volts RMS?"},{"questionId":"A-003-002-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"peak-envelope power"},{"letter":"B","text":"mean power"},{"letter":"C","text":"carrier power"},{"letter":"D","text":"full power"}],"questionText":"The power supplied to the antennatransmission line by a transmitter during anRF cycle at the highest crest of themodulation envelope is known as:"},{"questionId":"A-003-002-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"PIV"},{"letter":"B","text":"ERP"},{"letter":"C","text":"power factor"},{"letter":"D","text":"PEP"}],"questionText":"To compute one of the following, multiply thepeak-envelope voltage by 0.707 to obtain theRMS value, square the result and divide bythe load resistance. Which is the correctanswer?"},{"questionId":"A-003-002-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a hypothetical measurement"},{"letter":"B","text":"Peak-Envelope Voltage (PEV) multipliedby 0.707, squared and divided by the loadresistance"},{"letter":"C","text":"peak-voltage multiplied by peak current"},{"letter":"D","text":"equal to the RMS power"}],"questionText":"Peak-Envelope Power (PEP) for SSBtransmission is:"},{"questionId":"A-003-002-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"PEP = [(Vp)(Vp)] / (RL)"},{"letter":"B","text":"PEP = (Vp)(Vp)(RL)"},{"letter":"C","text":"PEP = [(1.414 PEV)(1.414 PEV)] / RL"},{"letter":"D","text":"PEP = [(0.707 PEV)(0.707 PEV)] / RL"}],"questionText":"How is the output Peak-Envelope Power of atransmitter calculated if an oscilloscope isused to measure the Peak-Envelope Voltageacross a dummy resistive load (where PEP= Peak-Envelope Power, PEV = Peak-Envelope Voltage, Vp = peak-voltage, RL =load resistance)?"},{"questionId":"A-003-002-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"400 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"1000 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"200 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"100 watts"}],"questionText":"What is the output PEP from a transmitter ifan oscilloscope measures 200 volts peak-to-peak across a 50-ohm dummy loadconnected to the transmitter output?"},{"questionId":"A-003-002-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"625 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"1250 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"2500 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"500 watts"}],"questionText":"What is the output PEP from a transmitter ifan oscilloscope measures 500 volts peak-to-peak across a 50-ohm dummy loadconnected to the transmitter output?"},{"questionId":"A-003-002-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2120 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"1500 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"530 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"1060 watts"}],"questionText":"What is the output PEP of an unmodulatedcarrier transmitter if a wattmeter connectedto the transmitter output indicates anaverage reading of 1060 watts?"},{"questionId":"A-003-002-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1000 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"400 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"200 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"600 watts"}],"questionText":"What is the output PEP from a transmitter, ifan oscilloscope measures 400 volts peak-to-peak across a 50 ohm dummy loadconnected to the transmitter output?"},{"questionId":"A-003-002-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1600 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"800 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"6400 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"3200 watts"}],"questionText":"What is the output PEP from a transmitter, ifan oscilloscope measures 800 volts peak-to-peak across a 50 ohm dummy loadconnected to the transmitter output?"},{"questionId":"A-003-002-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"625 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"427.5 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"884 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"442 watts"}],"questionText":"An oscilloscope measures 500 volts peak-to-peak across a 50 ohm dummy loadconnected to the transmitter output duringunmodulated carrier conditions. What wouldan average-reading power meter indicateunder the same transmitter conditions?"},{"questionId":"A-003-003-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An SWR meter"},{"letter":"B","text":"A marker generator"},{"letter":"C","text":"A field-strength meter"},{"letter":"D","text":"A variable frequency oscillator withmetered feedback current"}],"questionText":"What is a dip meter?"},{"questionId":"A-003-003-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To measure resonant frequency ofantenna traps and percentage modulation"},{"letter":"B","text":"To measure resonant frequencies ofantenna traps and to measure a tunedcircuit resonant frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"To measure antenna resonance andimpedance"},{"letter":"D","text":"To measure antenna resonance andpercentage modulation"}],"questionText":"What two ways could a dip meter be used inan amateur station?"},{"questionId":"A-003-003-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the impedance mismatch in a circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"the adjustment of an inductor"},{"letter":"C","text":"the resonant frequency of a circuit"},{"letter":"D","text":"the calibration of an absorption-typewavemeter"}],"questionText":"A dip meter supplies the radio frequencyenergy which enables you to check:"},{"questionId":"A-003-003-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"determine the frequency of oscillations"},{"letter":"B","text":"align receiver-tuned circuits"},{"letter":"C","text":"measure the value of capacitance orinductance"},{"letter":"D","text":"align transmitter-tuned circuits"}],"questionText":"A dip meter may not be used directly to:"},{"questionId":"A-003-003-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"reads half the true output when theattenuator is properly terminated"},{"letter":"B","text":"reads accurately only when theattenuator is properly terminated"},{"letter":"C","text":"always reads the true output of the signalgenerator"},{"letter":"D","text":"reads twice the true output when theattenuator is properly terminated"}],"questionText":"The dial calibration on the output attenuatorof a signal generator:"},{"questionId":"A-003-003-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A high-stability oscillator which canproduce a wide range of frequencies andamplitudes"},{"letter":"B","text":"A low-stability oscillator which sweepsthrough a range of frequencies"},{"letter":"C","text":"A low-stability oscillator used to inject asignal into a circuit under test"},{"letter":"D","text":"A high-stability oscillator which generatesreference signals at exact frequencyintervals"}],"questionText":"What is a signal generator?"},{"questionId":"A-003-003-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"should be loosely coupled to the circuitunder test"},{"letter":"B","text":"should be tightly coupled to the circuitunder test"},{"letter":"C","text":"may be used only with series tunedcircuits"},{"letter":"D","text":"accurately measures frequencies"}],"questionText":"A dip meter:"},{"questionId":"A-003-003-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Calibrated RF signal generator with FMtone modulation and total harmonicdistortion (THD) analyzer"},{"letter":"B","text":"RF signal generator with FM tonemodulation and a deviation meter"},{"letter":"C","text":"Oscilloscope and spectrum analyzer"},{"letter":"D","text":"Receiver noise bridge and total harmonicdistortion analyser"}],"questionText":"Which two instruments are needed tomeasure FM receiver sensitivity for a 12 dBSINAD ratio (signal + noise + distortion overnoise + distortion)?"},{"questionId":"A-003-003-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Transmitter power output"},{"letter":"B","text":"Hand capacity"},{"letter":"C","text":"Stray capacity"},{"letter":"D","text":"Over coupling"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is not a factoraffecting the frequency accuracy of a dipmeter?"},{"questionId":"A-003-004-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It produces a reference frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"It makes frequency measurements"},{"letter":"C","text":"It measures frequency deviation"},{"letter":"D","text":"It generates broad-band white noise forcalibration"}],"questionText":"What does a frequency counter do?"},{"questionId":"A-003-004-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Time base accuracy, speed of the logic,and time base stability"},{"letter":"B","text":"Time base accuracy, temperaturecoefficient of the logic and time basestability"},{"letter":"C","text":"Number of digits in the readout, speed ofthe logic, and time base stability"},{"letter":"D","text":"Number of digits in the readout, externalfrequency reference and temperaturecoefficient of the logic"}],"questionText":"What factors limit the accuracy, frequencyresponse and stability of a frequencycounter?"},{"questionId":"A-003-004-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"By improving the accuracy of thefrequency response"},{"letter":"B","text":"By increasing the accuracy of the timebase"},{"letter":"C","text":"By using slower digital logic"},{"letter":"D","text":"By using faster digital logic"}],"questionText":"How can the accuracy of a frequencycounter be improved?"},{"questionId":"A-003-004-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1.4652 Hz"},{"letter":"B","text":"1.4652 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"14.652 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.1 MHz"}],"questionText":"If a frequency counter with a time baseaccuracy of +/- 0.1 PPM (parts per million)reads 146 520 000 Hz, what is the most thatthe actual frequency being measured coulddiffer from that reading?"},{"questionId":"A-003-004-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1465.2 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"1465.2 Hz"},{"letter":"C","text":"146.52 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"146.52 kHz"}],"questionText":"If a frequency counter, with a time baseaccuracy of 10 PPM (parts per million) reads146 520 000 Hz, what is the most the actualfrequency being measured could differ fromthat reading?"},{"questionId":"A-003-004-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"crystal oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"self-oscillating Hartley oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"mechanical tuning fork"},{"letter":"D","text":"free-running multivibrator"}],"questionText":"The clock in a frequency counter normallyuses a:"},{"questionId":"A-003-004-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"type of display used in the counter"},{"letter":"B","text":"the number of digits displayed"},{"letter":"C","text":"the characteristics of the internal time-base generator"},{"letter":"D","text":"the size of the frequency counter"}],"questionText":"The frequency accuracy of a frequencycounter is determined by:"},{"questionId":"A-003-004-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Zero-beat the crystal oscillator against astandard frequency station such asWWV"},{"letter":"B","text":"Compare the oscillator with yourtransmitter"},{"letter":"C","text":"Use a dip-meter to determine theoscillator's fundamental frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"Compare the oscillator with your receiver"}],"questionText":"What is the traditional way of verifying theaccuracy of a crystal calibrator?"},{"questionId":"A-003-004-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"oven-controlled crystal oscillator (OCXO)"},{"letter":"B","text":"GPS disciplined oscillator (GPSDO)"},{"letter":"C","text":"voltage-controlled crystal oscillator(VCXO)"},{"letter":"D","text":"temperature compensated crystaloscillator (TCXO)"}],"questionText":"Out of the following oscillators, one is NOT,by itself, considered a high-stabilityreference:"},{"questionId":"A-003-004-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the mathematical mean of bothfrequencies"},{"letter":"B","text":"at the highest audio frequency possible"},{"letter":"C","text":"of a frequency as low as possible andwith a period as long as possible"},{"letter":"D","text":"a combined frequency above both"}],"questionText":"You want to calibrate your station frequencyreference to the WWV signal on yourreceiver. The resulting beat tone must be:"},{"questionId":"A-003-005-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A rectangular pattern 100 mm wide and150 mm high"},{"letter":"B","text":"An oval pattern 100 mm wide and 150mm high"},{"letter":"C","text":"A looping pattern with 100 horizontalloops and 150 vertical loops"},{"letter":"D","text":"A looping pattern with 3 horizontal loops,and 2 vertical loops"}],"questionText":"If a 100 Hz signal is fed to the horizontalinput of an oscilloscope and a 150 Hz signalis fed to the vertical input, what type ofpattern should be displayed on the screen?"},{"questionId":"A-003-005-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Accuracy of the time base and thelinearity and bandwidth of the deflectionamplifiers"},{"letter":"B","text":"Deflection amplifier output impedanceand tube face frequency increments"},{"letter":"C","text":"Accuracy and linearity of the time baseand tube face voltage increments"},{"letter":"D","text":"Tube face voltage increments anddeflection amplifier voltages"}],"questionText":"What factors limit the accuracy, frequencyresponse and stability of an oscilloscope?"},{"questionId":"A-003-005-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"By using triggered sweep and a crystaloscillator for the timebase"},{"letter":"B","text":"By increasing the horizontal sweep rateand the vertical amplifier frequencyresponse"},{"letter":"C","text":"By using a crystal oscillator as the timebase and increasing the vertical sweeprate"},{"letter":"D","text":"By increasing the vertical sweep rate andthe horizontal amplifier frequencyresponse"}],"questionText":"How can the frequency response of anoscilloscope be improved?"},{"questionId":"A-003-005-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"measuring the input on the X axis and theoutput on the Z axis"},{"letter":"B","text":"measuring the input on the Y axis andthe output on the X axis"},{"letter":"C","text":"utilizing a dual trace oscilloscope"},{"letter":"D","text":"measuring the input on the X axis and theoutput on the Y axis"}],"questionText":"You can use an oscilloscope to display theinput and output of a circuit at the sametime by:"},{"questionId":"A-003-005-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"directly related to gain compression"},{"letter":"B","text":"indirectly related to screen persistence"},{"letter":"C","text":"a function of the time-base accuracy"},{"letter":"D","text":"the highest frequency signal the scopecan display"}],"questionText":"The bandwidth of an oscilloscope is:"},{"questionId":"A-003-005-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"an ellipse"},{"letter":"B","text":"a circle"},{"letter":"C","text":"a diagonal straight line"},{"letter":"D","text":"a horizontal straight line"}],"questionText":"When using Lissajous figures to determinephase differences, an indication of zero or180 degrees is represented on the screen ofan oscilloscope by:"},{"questionId":"A-003-005-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"30 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"40 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"20 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"50 kHz"}],"questionText":"A 100-kHz signal is applied to the horizontalchannel of an oscilloscope. A signal ofunknown frequency is applied to the verticalchannel. The resultant wave form has 5loops displayed vertically and 2 loopshorizontally. The unknown frequency is:"},{"questionId":"A-003-005-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"through the addition of a high-value seriesresistor"},{"letter":"B","text":"when measuring a signal whosefrequency varies"},{"letter":"C","text":"every time the probe is usde with adifferent oscilloscope"},{"letter":"D","text":"when measuring a sine wave"}],"questionText":"An oscilloscope probe must becompensated:"},{"questionId":"A-003-005-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A signal tracer and an audio amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"A field-strength meter"},{"letter":"C","text":"An oscilloscope"},{"letter":"D","text":"A sidetone monitor"}],"questionText":"What is the best instrument to use to checkthe signal quality of a CW or single-sidebandphone transmitter?"},{"questionId":"A-003-005-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The RF output of the transmitter througha sampling device"},{"letter":"B","text":"The RF signals of a nearby receivingantenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"The IF output of a monitoring receiver"},{"letter":"D","text":"The audio input of the transmitter"}],"questionText":"What is the best signal source to connect tothe vertical input of an oscilloscope forchecking the quality of a transmitted signal?"},{"questionId":"A-003-006-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"40 ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"4 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"24 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"16 ohms"}],"questionText":"A meter has a full-scale deflection of 40microamperes and an internal resistance of96 ohms. You want it to read 0 to 1 mA. Thevalue of the shunt to be used is:"},{"questionId":"A-003-006-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"series resistance of 1 999.5 ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"shunt resistance of 19 999.5 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"shunt resistance of 19.5 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"series resistance of 19 999.5 ohms"}],"questionText":"A moving-coil milliammeter having a full-scale deflection of 1 mA and an internalresistance of 0.5 ohms is to be converted toa voltmeter of 20 volts full-scale deflection. Itwould be necessary to insert a:"},{"questionId":"A-003-006-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1 200 000 ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"600 000 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"1 500 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"750 000 ohms"}],"questionText":"A voltmeter having a range of 150 volts andan internal resistance of 150 000 ohms is tobe extended to read 750 volts. The requiredmultiplier resistor would have a value of:"},{"questionId":"A-003-006-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"50 microampere meter"},{"letter":"B","text":"1 milliampere meter"},{"letter":"C","text":"50 milliampere meter"},{"letter":"D","text":"100 milliampere meter"}],"questionText":"Voltmeter sensitivity is usually expressed inohms per volt. This means that a voltmeterwith a sensitivity of 20 kilohms per volt wouldbe a:"},{"questionId":"A-003-006-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"10 000 ohms per volt"},{"letter":"B","text":"150 ohms per volt"},{"letter":"C","text":"1000 ohms per volt"},{"letter":"D","text":"100 000 ohms per volt"}],"questionText":"The sensitivity of a voltmeter, whoseresistance is 150 000 ohms on the 150-voltrange, is:"},{"questionId":"A-003-006-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"changing the internal inductance of themeter"},{"letter":"B","text":"changing the internal capacitance of themeter to resonance"},{"letter":"C","text":"connecting an external resistance inparallel with the internal resistance"},{"letter":"D","text":"connecting an external resistance inseries with the internal resistance"}],"questionText":"The range of a DC ammeter can easily beextended by:"},{"questionId":"A-003-006-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Resistance is reduced in series with themeter"},{"letter":"B","text":"Resistance is reduced in parallel with themeter"},{"letter":"C","text":"Resistance is added in parallel with themeter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Resistance is added in series with themeter"}],"questionText":"What happens inside a multimeter when youswitch it from a lower to a higher voltagerange?"},{"questionId":"A-003-006-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"By adding resistance in parallel with thecircuit under test"},{"letter":"B","text":"By adding resistance in series with themeter"},{"letter":"C","text":"By adding resistance in parallel with themeter"},{"letter":"D","text":"By adding resistance in series with thecircuit under test"}],"questionText":"How can the range of an ammeter beincreased?"},{"questionId":"A-003-006-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"At the transmitter output connector"},{"letter":"B","text":"One-half wavelength from the transmitteroutput"},{"letter":"C","text":"One-half wavelength from the antennafeed point"},{"letter":"D","text":"At the antenna feed point"}],"questionText":"Where should an RF wattmeter beconnected for the most accurate readings oftransmitter output power?"},{"questionId":"A-003-006-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"25 ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"100 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"300 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"50 ohms"}],"questionText":"At what line impedance do most RFwattmeters usually operate?"},{"questionId":"A-004-001-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Full-wave centre-tap"},{"letter":"B","text":"Bridge"},{"letter":"C","text":"Half-wave"},{"letter":"D","text":"Quarter-wave"}],"questionText":"For the same transformer secondary voltage,which rectifier has the highest averageoutput voltage?"},{"questionId":"A-004-001-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2.8"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.636"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.707"},{"letter":"D","text":"1.4"}],"questionText":"In a full-wave centre-tap power supply,regardless of load conditions, the peakinverse voltage (PIV) will be _____ times theRMS voltage:"},{"questionId":"A-004-001-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a centre-tapped secondary on thetransformer"},{"letter":"B","text":"any output filtering"},{"letter":"C","text":"a centre-tapped primary on thetransformer"},{"letter":"D","text":"diodes across each leg of the transformer"}],"questionText":"A full-wave bridge rectifier circuit makes useof both halves of the AC cycle, but unlike thefull-wave centre-tap rectifier circuit it doesnot require:"},{"questionId":"A-004-001-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"half that of the full-wave centre-taprectifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"the same as the full-wave centre-taprectifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"the same as the half-wave rectifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"double that of the full-wave centre-taprectifier"}],"questionText":"For a given transformer the maximum outputvoltage available from a full-wave bridgerectifier circuit will be:"},{"questionId":"A-004-001-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"120 Hz"},{"letter":"B","text":"60 Hz"},{"letter":"C","text":"90 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"30 Hz"}],"questionText":"The ripple frequency produced by a full-wavepower supply connected to a normalhousehold circuit is:"},{"questionId":"A-004-001-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"60 Hz"},{"letter":"B","text":"90 Hz"},{"letter":"C","text":"120 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"30 Hz"}],"questionText":"The ripple frequency produced by a half-wavepower supply connected to a normalhousehold circuit is:"},{"questionId":"A-004-001-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"use both halves of an AC wave"},{"letter":"B","text":"create four times the output voltage ofhalf-wave doublers"},{"letter":"C","text":"use less power than half-wave doublers"},{"letter":"D","text":"are used only in high-frequency powersupplies"}],"questionText":"Full-wave voltage doublers:"},{"questionId":"A-004-001-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Peak load impedance; peak voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"Peak inverse voltage; average forwardcurrent"},{"letter":"C","text":"Average power; average voltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"Capacitive reactance; avalanche voltage"}],"questionText":"What are the two major ratings that mustnot be exceeded for silicon-diode rectifiersused in power-supply circuits?"},{"questionId":"A-004-001-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To decrease the output voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"To ensure that the current through eachdiode is about the same"},{"letter":"C","text":"To equalize voltage drops and guardagainst transient voltage spikes"},{"letter":"D","text":"To smooth the output waveform"}],"questionText":"In a high voltage power supply, why should aresistor and capacitor be wired in parallelwith the power-supply rectifier diodes?"},{"questionId":"A-004-001-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A series of pulses at twice the frequencyof the AC input"},{"letter":"B","text":"A steady DC voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"A sine wave at half the frequency of theAC input"},{"letter":"D","text":"A series of pulses at the same frequencyas the AC input"}],"questionText":"What is the output waveform of an unfilteredfull-wave rectifier connected to a resistiveload?"},{"questionId":"A-004-002-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A half-wave rectifier with a choke inputfilter"},{"letter":"B","text":"A full-wave rectifier with a capacitor inputfilter"},{"letter":"C","text":"A full-wave rectifier with a choke inputfilter"},{"letter":"D","text":"A half-wave bridge rectifier with acapacitor input filter"}],"questionText":"Which of the following circuits gives the bestregulation, under similar load conditions?"},{"questionId":"A-004-002-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"lower peak rectifier currents"},{"letter":"B","text":"a higher terminal voltage output"},{"letter":"C","text":"better filtering action or smaller ripplevoltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"improved voltage regulation"}],"questionText":"The advantage of the capacitor input filterover the choke input filter is:"},{"questionId":"A-004-002-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"greatest ripple frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"highest output voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"best regulated output"},{"letter":"D","text":"greatest percentage of ripple"}],"questionText":"With a normal load, the choke input filter willgive the:"},{"questionId":"A-004-002-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"choke input and capacitor input"},{"letter":"B","text":"choke output and capacitor output"},{"letter":"C","text":"choke input and capacitor output"},{"letter":"D","text":"choke output and capacitor input"}],"questionText":"There are two types of filters in general usein a power supply. They are called:"},{"questionId":"A-004-002-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"act as a secondary smoothing device inconjunction with the filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"improve voltage regulation"},{"letter":"C","text":"provide a ground return for the transformer"},{"letter":"D","text":"inhibit the flow of current through thesupply"}],"questionText":"The main function of the bleeder resistor in apower supply is to provide a discharge pathfor the capacitor in the power supply. But itmay also be used for a secondary function,which is to:"},{"questionId":"A-004-002-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"readily pass the DC and the ACcomponent"},{"letter":"B","text":"impede the passage of DC but will passthe AC component"},{"letter":"C","text":"impede both DC and AC"},{"letter":"D","text":"readily pass the DC but will impede theflow of the AC component"}],"questionText":"In a power supply, series chokes will:"},{"questionId":"A-004-002-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"utilizing a full-wave bridge rectifier circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"placing an ammeter in the output circuit"},{"letter":"C","text":"increasing the value of the outputcapacitor"},{"letter":"D","text":"including a suitable bleeder resistance"}],"questionText":"When using a choke input filter, a minimumcurrent should be drawn all the time whenthe device is switched on. This can beaccomplished by:"},{"questionId":"A-004-002-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"first choke and first capacitor"},{"letter":"B","text":"the bleeder resistor and the first choke"},{"letter":"C","text":"first capacitor and second capacitor"},{"letter":"D","text":"first choke and second capacitor"}],"questionText":"In the design of a power supply, the designermust be careful of resonance effectsbecause the ripple voltage could build up toa high value. The components that must becarefully selected are:"},{"questionId":"A-004-002-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Under no-load conditions and a burned-out bleeder, voltages could reach thepeak transformer voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"Resonance can be set up in the filterproducing high voltages"},{"letter":"C","text":"Under heavy load, high currents andvoltages are produced"},{"letter":"D","text":"Under no-load conditions, the currentcould reach a high level"}],"questionText":"In a properly designed choke input filterpower supply, the no-load voltage across thefilter capacitor will be about nine-tenths ofthe AC RMS voltage; yet it is advisable touse capacitors rated at the peak transformervoltage. Why is this large safety marginsuggested?"},{"questionId":"A-004-003-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The conduction of a control element isvaried in direct proportion to the linevoltage or load current"},{"letter":"B","text":"It has a ramp voltage at its output"},{"letter":"C","text":"A pass transistor switches from its \"on\"state to its \"off\" state"},{"letter":"D","text":"The control device is switched on or off,with the duty cycle proportional to theline or load conditions"}],"questionText":"What is one characteristic of a linearelectronic voltage regulator?"},{"questionId":"A-004-003-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It provides more than one output voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"It gives a ramp voltage at its output"},{"letter":"C","text":"The control device is switched on and off,with the duty cycle proportional to theline or load conditions"},{"letter":"D","text":"The conduction of a control element isvaried in direct proportion to the linevoltage or load current"}],"questionText":"What is one characteristic of a switchingvoltage regulator?"},{"questionId":"A-004-003-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A junction diode"},{"letter":"B","text":"A Zener diode"},{"letter":"C","text":"An SCR"},{"letter":"D","text":"A varactor diode"}],"questionText":"What device is typically used as a stablereference voltage in a linear voltageregulator?"},{"questionId":"A-004-003-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A shunt regulator"},{"letter":"B","text":"A constant current source"},{"letter":"C","text":"A shunt current source"},{"letter":"D","text":"A series regulator"}],"questionText":"What type of linear regulator is used inapplications requiring efficient utilization ofthe primary power source?"},{"questionId":"A-004-003-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A shunt regulator"},{"letter":"B","text":"A constant current source"},{"letter":"C","text":"A shunt current source"},{"letter":"D","text":"A series regulator"}],"questionText":"What type of linear voltage regulator is usedin applications requiring a constant load onthe unregulated voltage source?"},{"questionId":"A-004-003-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A feedback connection to an erroramplifier is made directly to the load"},{"letter":"B","text":"An error amplifier compares the inputvoltage to the reference voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"A load connection is made outside thefeedback loop"},{"letter":"D","text":"By wireless inductive loops"}],"questionText":"How is remote sensing accomplished in alinear voltage regulator?"},{"questionId":"A-004-003-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Maximum output voltage and minimumoutput current"},{"letter":"B","text":"Minimum output voltage and maximumoutput current"},{"letter":"C","text":"Output voltage and minimum outputcurrent"},{"letter":"D","text":"Output voltage and maximum outputcurrent"}],"questionText":"In addition to an input voltage range what arethe important characteristics of a three-terminal regulator?"},{"questionId":"A-004-003-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A three-terminal regulator"},{"letter":"B","text":"An op-amp regulator"},{"letter":"C","text":"A switching regulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"A Zener regulator"}],"questionText":"What type of voltage regulator contains avoltage reference, error amplifier, sensingresistors and transistors, and a passelement in one package?"},{"questionId":"A-004-003-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"linear and switching"},{"letter":"B","text":"non-linear and switching"},{"letter":"C","text":"linear and non-linear"},{"letter":"D","text":"stiff and switching"}],"questionText":"When extremely low ripple is required, orwhen the voltage supplied to the load mustremain constant under conditions of largefluctuations of current and line voltage, aclosed-loop amplifier is used to regulate thepower supply. There are two main categoriesof electronic regulators. They are:"},{"questionId":"A-004-003-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"regulator six-terminal regulator"},{"letter":"B","text":"three-terminal regulator"},{"letter":"C","text":"nine-pin terminal regulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"twenty-four pin terminal"}],"questionText":"A modern type of regulator, which features areference, high-gain amplifier, temperature-compensated voltage sensing resistors andtransistors as well as a pass element iscommonly referred to as a:"},{"questionId":"A-004-004-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"indirectly proportional to the load voltageand the input/output voltage differential"},{"letter":"B","text":"directly proportional to the load currentand the input/output voltage differential"},{"letter":"C","text":"the inverse of the load current and theinput/output voltage differential"},{"letter":"D","text":"dependent upon the peak inverse voltageappearing across the Zener diode"}],"questionText":"In a series-regulated power supply, thepower dissipation of the pass transistor is:"},{"questionId":"A-004-004-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"at the point where the sampling networkor error amplifier is connected"},{"letter":"B","text":"across the secondary of the passtransistor"},{"letter":"C","text":"across the load"},{"letter":"D","text":"at the output of the pass transistor"}],"questionText":"In any regulated power supply, the output iscleanest and the regulation is best:"},{"questionId":"A-004-004-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"ideal"},{"letter":"B","text":"rectifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"differential"},{"letter":"D","text":"load"}],"questionText":"When discussing a power supplythe_______ resistance is equal to the outputvoltage divided by the total current drawn,including the current drawn by the bleederresistor:"},{"questionId":"A-004-004-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"dynamic regulation"},{"letter":"B","text":"static regulation"},{"letter":"C","text":"active regulation"},{"letter":"D","text":"analog regulation"}],"questionText":"The regulation of long-term changes in theload resistance of a power supply is called:"},{"questionId":"A-004-004-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the choke"},{"letter":"B","text":"the input capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"the bleeder resistor"},{"letter":"D","text":"the output capacitor"}],"questionText":"The dynamic regulation of a power supply isimproved by increasing the value of:"},{"questionId":"A-004-004-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the negative terminal of the electrolyticcapacitor is connected to the positive andthe positive terminal to ground"},{"letter":"B","text":"a battery is placed in series with theoutput capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"it is placed in series with other capacitors"},{"letter":"D","text":"the output capacitance is increased"}],"questionText":"The output capacitor, in a power supply filterused to provide power for an SSB or CWtransmitter, will give better dynamicregulation if:"},{"questionId":"A-004-004-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a tuning network"},{"letter":"B","text":"a rectifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"equalization across the transformer"},{"letter":"D","text":"matching between the secondary of thepower transformer and the filter"}],"questionText":"In a regulated power supply, four diodesconnected together in a BRIDGE act as:"},{"questionId":"A-004-004-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"capacitors"},{"letter":"B","text":"diodes"},{"letter":"C","text":"chokes"},{"letter":"D","text":"fuses"}],"questionText":"In a regulated power supply, componentsthat conduct alternating current at the inputbefore the transformer and direct currentbefore the output are:"},{"questionId":"A-004-004-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"voltage regulator"},{"letter":"B","text":"pi filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"solid-state by-pass circuit"},{"letter":"D","text":"matching circuit for the load"}],"questionText":"In a regulated power supply, the output ofthe electrolytic filter capacitor is connectedto the:"},{"questionId":"A-004-004-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"protect the regulator from reversevoltages"},{"letter":"B","text":"provide an RF by-pass for the voltagecontrol"},{"letter":"C","text":"provide additional capacity"},{"letter":"D","text":"protect the regulator from voltagefluctuations in the primary of thetransformer"}],"questionText":"In a regulated power supply, a diodeconnected across the input and outputterminals of a regulator is used to:"},{"questionId":"A-005-001-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Through a neutralizing capacitor"},{"letter":"B","text":"Through a tapped coil"},{"letter":"C","text":"Through a capacitive divider"},{"letter":"D","text":"Through link coupling"}],"questionText":"How is the positive feedback coupled to theinput in a Hartley oscillator?"},{"questionId":"A-005-001-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Through a link coupling"},{"letter":"B","text":"Through a capacitive divider"},{"letter":"C","text":"Through a tapped coil"},{"letter":"D","text":"Through a neutralizing capacitor"}],"questionText":"How is positive feedback coupled to theinput in a Colpitts oscillator?"},{"questionId":"A-005-001-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Through capacitive coupling"},{"letter":"B","text":"Through a neutralizing capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"Through link coupling"},{"letter":"D","text":"Through a tapped coil"}],"questionText":"How is positive feedback coupled to theinput in a Pierce oscillator?"},{"questionId":"A-005-001-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Any amplitude variations in the referenceoscillator signal will prevent the loop fromchanging frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"Any amplitude variations in the referenceoscillator signal will prevent the loop fromlocking to the desired signal"},{"letter":"C","text":"Any phase variations in the referenceoscillator signal will produce phase noisein the synthesizer output"},{"letter":"D","text":"Any phase variations in the referenceoscillator signal will produce harmonicdistortion in the modulating signal"}],"questionText":"Why must a very stable reference oscillatorbe used as part of a phase-locked loop(PLL) frequency synthesizer?"},{"questionId":"A-005-001-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Pierce"},{"letter":"B","text":"Hartley"},{"letter":"C","text":"Miller"},{"letter":"D","text":"Colpitts"}],"questionText":"Positive feedback from a capacitive dividerindicates the oscillator type is:"},{"questionId":"A-005-001-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Mylar"},{"letter":"B","text":"silver mica"},{"letter":"C","text":"ceramic"},{"letter":"D","text":"electrolytics"}],"questionText":"In an RF oscillator circuit designed for highstability, the positive feedback is drawn fromtwo capacitors connected in series. Thesetwo capacitors would most likely be:"},{"questionId":"A-005-001-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Colpitts"},{"letter":"B","text":"Hartley"},{"letter":"C","text":"Miller"},{"letter":"D","text":"Pierce"}],"questionText":"In an oscillator circuit where positivefeedback is obtained through a singlecapacitor in series with the crystal, the typeof oscillator is:"},{"questionId":"A-005-001-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"detector"},{"letter":"B","text":"audio amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"variable-frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"D","text":"mixer"}],"questionText":"A circuit depending on positive feedback forits operation would be a:"},{"questionId":"A-005-001-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a fixed-frequency single-sidebandtransmitter"},{"letter":"B","text":"a two-stage frequency-modulatedtransmitter"},{"letter":"C","text":"a two-stage regenerative receiver"},{"letter":"D","text":"a two-stage CW transmitter"}],"questionText":"An apparatus with an oscillator and a classC amplifier would be:"},{"questionId":"A-005-001-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Franklin"},{"letter":"B","text":"Pierce"},{"letter":"C","text":"Colpitts"},{"letter":"D","text":"Hartley"}],"questionText":"In an oscillator where positive feedback isprovided through a capacitor in series with acrystal, that type of oscillator is a:"},{"questionId":"A-005-002-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"are involved with frequency multiplicationin the previous stage"},{"letter":"B","text":"allow efficient transfer of power to theantenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"allow switching to different antennas"},{"letter":"D","text":"reduce the possibility of cross-modulationin adjunct receivers"}],"questionText":"The output tuning controls on a transmitterpower amplifier with an adjustable PInetwork:"},{"questionId":"A-005-002-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the cathode"},{"letter":"B","text":"the plate"},{"letter":"C","text":"the control grid"},{"letter":"D","text":"the filament leads"}],"questionText":"In a grounded grid amplifier using a triodevacuum tube, the input signal is applied to:"},{"questionId":"A-005-002-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"blocking capacitor"},{"letter":"B","text":"by-pass capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"tuning capacitor"},{"letter":"D","text":"electrolytic capacitor"}],"questionText":"In a grounded grid amplifier using a triodevacuum tube, the plate is connected to thepi-network through a:"},{"questionId":"A-005-002-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"B+ (high voltage)"},{"letter":"B","text":"filament voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"ground"},{"letter":"D","text":"B- (bias)"}],"questionText":"In a grounded grid amplifier using a triodevacuum tube, the plate is connected to aradio frequency choke. The other end of theradio frequency choke connects to the:"},{"questionId":"A-005-002-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"B+ (high voltage)"},{"letter":"B","text":"B- (bias)"},{"letter":"C","text":"ground"},{"letter":"D","text":"filament voltage"}],"questionText":"In a grounded grid amplifier using a triodevacuum tube, the cathode is connected to aradio frequency choke. The other end of theradio frequency choke connects to the:"},{"questionId":"A-005-002-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"B- (bias)"},{"letter":"B","text":"B+ (high voltage)"},{"letter":"C","text":"Screen voltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"filament voltage"}],"questionText":"In a grounded grid amplifier using a triodevacuum tube, the secondary winding of atransformer is connected directly to thevacuum tube. This transformer provides:"},{"questionId":"A-005-002-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2000 volts"},{"letter":"B","text":"500 volts"},{"letter":"C","text":"3000 volts"},{"letter":"D","text":"1000 volts"}],"questionText":"In a grounded grid amplifier using a triodevacuum tube, what would be theapproximate B+ voltage required for anoutput of 400 watts at 400 mA withapproximately 50 percent efficiency?"},{"questionId":"A-005-002-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"by-pass capacitors"},{"letter":"B","text":"tuning capacitors"},{"letter":"C","text":"electrolytic capacitors"},{"letter":"D","text":"blocking capacitors"}],"questionText":"In a grounded grid amplifier using a triodevacuum tube, each side of the filament isconnected to a capacitor whose other end isconnected to ground. These are:"},{"questionId":"A-005-002-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Make sure that the power interlockswitch is bypassed so you can test theamplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"Be certain no antenna is attached so thatyou will not cause any interference"},{"letter":"C","text":"Remove all amplifier shielding to ensuremaximum cooling"},{"letter":"D","text":"Be certain all amplifier shielding isfastened in place"}],"questionText":"After you have opened a VHF poweramplifier to make internal tuningadjustments, what should you do before youturn the amplifier on?"},{"questionId":"A-005-003-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"be part of a tuned circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"act as part of a pi filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"provide the necessary feedback foroscillation"},{"letter":"D","text":"act as part of a balanced mixer"}],"questionText":"In a simple 2 stage CW transmitter circuit,the oscillator stage and the class C amplifierstage are inductively coupled by a RFtransformer. Another role of the RFtransformer is to:"},{"questionId":"A-005-003-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"form a RF-tuned circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"form a low-pass filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"provide negative feedback"},{"letter":"D","text":"form a key-click filter"}],"questionText":"In a simple 2 stage CW transmitter, currentto the collector of the transistor in the classC amplifier stage flows through a radiofrequency choke (RFC) and a tappedinductor. The RFC, on the tapped inductorside, is also connected to groundedcapacitors. The purpose of the RFC andcapacitors is to:"},{"questionId":"A-005-003-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the master oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"an audio oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"a power amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"a frequency multiplier"}],"questionText":"In a simple 2 stage CW transmitter, thetransistor in the second stage would act as:"},{"questionId":"A-005-003-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"changes in oscillator frequency are lesslikely"},{"letter":"B","text":"key clicks are eliminated"},{"letter":"C","text":"the radiated bandwidth is restricted"},{"letter":"D","text":"high RF voltages are not present"}],"questionText":"An advantage of keying the buffer stage in atransmitter is that:"},{"questionId":"A-005-003-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A minimum change in grid current as theoutput circuit is changed"},{"letter":"B","text":"Minimum grid current"},{"letter":"C","text":"Maximum grid current"},{"letter":"D","text":"A maximum change in grid current as theoutput circuit is changed"}],"questionText":"As a power amplifier is tuned, what readingon its grid current meter indicates the bestneutralization?"},{"questionId":"A-005-003-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It eliminates AC hum from the powersupply"},{"letter":"B","text":"It reduces incidental grid modulation"},{"letter":"C","text":"It controls differential gain"},{"letter":"D","text":"It cancels the effects of positive feedback"}],"questionText":"What does a neutralizing circuit do in an RFamplifier?"},{"questionId":"A-005-003-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To limit the modulation index"},{"letter":"B","text":"To cut off the final amplifier duringstandby periods"},{"letter":"C","text":"To keep the carrier on frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"To eliminate parasitic oscillations"}],"questionText":"What is the reason for neutralizing the finalamplifier stage of a transmitter?"},{"questionId":"A-005-003-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"accidental resonant frequencies in thepower amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"harmonics from some earlier multiplierstage"},{"letter":"C","text":"excessive drive or excitation to the poweramplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"a mismatch between power amplifier andtransmission line"}],"questionText":"Parasitic oscillations are usually generateddue to:"},{"questionId":"A-005-003-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To cancel AC hum from the filamenttransformer"},{"letter":"B","text":"To reduce the limits of loaded Q"},{"letter":"C","text":"To cancel oscillation caused by theeffects of interelectrode capacitance"},{"letter":"D","text":"To reduce grid-to-cathode leakage"}],"questionText":"Why is neutralization necessary for somevacuum-tube amplifiers?"},{"questionId":"A-005-003-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"lack of neutralization"},{"letter":"B","text":"overdriven stages"},{"letter":"C","text":"poor voltage regulation"},{"letter":"D","text":"excessive harmonic production"}],"questionText":"Parasitic oscillations in an RF poweramplifier may be caused by:"},{"questionId":"A-005-004-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Single sideband, suppressed carrier"},{"letter":"B","text":"Double sideband, suppressed carrier"},{"letter":"C","text":"FM with balanced deviation"},{"letter":"D","text":"Full carrier"}],"questionText":"What type of signal does a balancedmodulator produce?"},{"questionId":"A-005-004-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"By using a balanced modulator followedby a filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"By driving a product detector with a DSBsignal"},{"letter":"C","text":"By using a loop modulator followed by amixer"},{"letter":"D","text":"By using a reactance modulator followedby a mixer"}],"questionText":"How can a single-sideband phone signal beproduced?"},{"questionId":"A-005-004-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the mechanical filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"the frequency multiplier stage"},{"letter":"C","text":"the balanced modulator stage"},{"letter":"D","text":"the carrier decouple stage"}],"questionText":"Carrier suppression in a single-sidebandtransmitter takes place in:"},{"questionId":"A-005-004-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3 dB gain in the transmitter"},{"letter":"B","text":"6 dB gain in the transmitter and 3 dBgain in the receiver"},{"letter":"C","text":"6 dB gain in the receiver"},{"letter":"D","text":"a greater bandpass requirement in thereceiver"}],"questionText":"Transmission with SSB, as compared toconventional AM transmission, results in:"},{"questionId":"A-005-004-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"twice the RF power output of any of thetones"},{"letter":"B","text":"equal to the RF peak output power of anyof the tones"},{"letter":"C","text":"one-half of the RF peak output power ofany of the tones"},{"letter":"D","text":"one-quarter of the RF peak output powerof any of the tones"}],"questionText":"The peak power output of a single-sidebandtransmitter, when being tested by a two-tonegenerator is:"},{"questionId":"A-005-004-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Normal speech"},{"letter":"B","text":"Two audio-frequency sine waves"},{"letter":"C","text":"An audio-frequency sine wave"},{"letter":"D","text":"An audio-frequency square wave"}],"questionText":"What kind of input signal is used to test theamplitude linearity of a single-sidebandphone transmitter while viewing the outputon an oscilloscope?"},{"questionId":"A-005-004-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"20 Hz and 20 kHz tones must be used"},{"letter":"B","text":"1200 Hz and 2400 Hz tones must beused"},{"letter":"C","text":"Any two audio tones may be used, butthey must be within the transmitter audiopassband, and must be harmonicallyrelated"},{"letter":"D","text":"Any two audio tones may be used, butthey must be within the transmitter audiopassband, and should not beharmonically related"}],"questionText":"What audio frequencies are used in a two-tone test of the linearity of a single-sidebandphone transmitter?"},{"questionId":"A-005-004-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Its linearity"},{"letter":"B","text":"Its frequency deviation"},{"letter":"C","text":"Its percent of carrier phase shift"},{"letter":"D","text":"Its percent of frequency modulation"}],"questionText":"What measurement can be made of asingle-sideband phone transmitter's amplifierby performing a two-tone test using anoscilloscope?"},{"questionId":"A-005-004-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"At least 40 dB"},{"letter":"B","text":"No more than 20 dB"},{"letter":"C","text":"No more than 30 dB"},{"letter":"D","text":"At least 60 dB"}],"questionText":"How much is the carrier suppressed belowpeak output power in a single-sidebandphone transmission?"},{"questionId":"A-005-004-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The transmitter's carrier is properlysuppressed"},{"letter":"B","text":"Signal distortion caused by excessivedrive"},{"letter":"C","text":"Signal distortion caused by insufficientcollector current"},{"letter":"D","text":"The transmitter's automatic level controlis properly adjusted"}],"questionText":"What is meant by \"flat topping\" in a single-sideband phone transmission?"},{"questionId":"A-005-005-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1000"},{"letter":"B","text":"3"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.3"},{"letter":"D","text":"3000"}],"questionText":"In an FM phone signal having a maximumfrequency deviation of 3000 Hz either side ofthe carrier frequency, what is the modulationindex, when the modulating frequency is1000 Hz?"},{"questionId":"A-005-005-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2000"},{"letter":"B","text":"6000"},{"letter":"C","text":"3"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.333"}],"questionText":"What is the modulation index of an FMphone transmitter producing aninstantaneous carrier deviation of 6 kHzwhen modulated with a 2 kHz modulatingfrequency?"},{"questionId":"A-005-005-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"0.6"},{"letter":"B","text":"1.66"},{"letter":"C","text":"60"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.16"}],"questionText":"What is the deviation ratio of an FM phonetransmitter having a maximum frequencyswing of plus or minus 5 kHz and acceptinga maximum modulation rate of 3 kHz?"},{"questionId":"A-005-005-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"centre frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"frequency deviation"},{"letter":"C","text":"frequency shift"},{"letter":"D","text":"modulating frequency"}],"questionText":"When the transmitter is not modulated, orthe amplitude of the modulating signal iszero, the frequency of the carrier is calledits:"},{"questionId":"A-005-005-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"amplitude and the frequency of themodulating frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"modulating frequency and the amplitudeof the centre frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"amplitude of the modulating frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"frequency of the modulating frequency"}],"questionText":"In an FM transmitter system, the amount ofdeviation from the centre frequency isdetermined solely by the:"},{"questionId":"A-005-005-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"four sideband frequencies"},{"letter":"B","text":"one sideband frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"an infinite number of sidebandfrequencies"},{"letter":"D","text":"two sideband frequencies"}],"questionText":"Any FM wave with single-tone modulationhas:"},{"questionId":"A-005-005-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a carrier peak and dividing by themodulation index"},{"letter":"B","text":"a carrier null and multiplying themodulation frequency by the modulationindex"},{"letter":"C","text":"detecting the frequencies in thesidebands"},{"letter":"D","text":"the amplitude of power in the sidebands"}],"questionText":"Some types of deviation meters work on theprinciple of:"},{"questionId":"A-005-005-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"pass-band of the IF filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"modulating frequency and the modulationindex"},{"letter":"C","text":"modulation index"},{"letter":"D","text":"modulating frequency"}],"questionText":"When using some deviation meters, it isimportant to know:"},{"questionId":"A-005-005-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"8 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"5 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"3 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"16 kHz"}],"questionText":"What is the significant bandwidth of an FM-phone transmission having a +/- 5-kHzdeviation and a 3-kHz modulating frequency?"},{"questionId":"A-005-005-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"+/- 416.7 Hz"},{"letter":"B","text":"+/- 12 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"+/- 5 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"+/- 41.67 Hz"}],"questionText":"What is the frequency deviation for a 12.21-MHz reactance-modulated oscillator in a +/-5-kHz deviation, 146.52-MHz FM-phonetransmitter?"},{"questionId":"A-005-006-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Amplifier desensitization"},{"letter":"B","text":"Intermodulation interference"},{"letter":"C","text":"Neutralization"},{"letter":"D","text":"Adjacent channel interference"}],"questionText":"If the signals of two repeater transmittersmix together in one or both of their finalamplifiers and unwanted signals at the sumand difference frequencies of the originalsignals are generated and radiated, what isthis called?"},{"questionId":"A-005-006-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"By using a Class C final amplifier withhigh driving power"},{"letter":"B","text":"By installing a terminated circulator orferrite isolator in the transmission line tothe transmitter and duplexer"},{"letter":"C","text":"By installing a low-pass filter in theantenna transmission line"},{"letter":"D","text":"By installing a high-pass filter in theantenna transmission line"}],"questionText":"How can intermodulation interferencebetween two repeater transmitters in closeproximity often be reduced or eliminated?"},{"questionId":"A-005-006-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"73.35 MHz and 239.40 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"146.34 MHz and 146.61 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"146.88 MHz and 146.34 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"146.01 MHz and 147.30 MHz"}],"questionText":"If a receiver tuned to 146.70 MHz receivesan intermodulation product signal whenevera nearby transmitter transmits on 146.52,what are the two most likely frequencies forthe other interfering signal?"},{"questionId":"A-005-006-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A phase modulator"},{"letter":"B","text":"A balanced modulator"},{"letter":"C","text":"A double balanced mixer"},{"letter":"D","text":"An audio modulator"}],"questionText":"What type of circuit varies the tuning of anamplifier tank circuit to produce FM signals?"},{"questionId":"A-005-006-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A heterodyne suppressor"},{"letter":"B","text":"A de-emphasis network"},{"letter":"C","text":"A pre-emphasis network"},{"letter":"D","text":"An audio prescaler"}],"questionText":"What audio shaping network is added at anFM transmitter to attenuate the lower audiofrequencies?"},{"questionId":"A-005-006-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An L-C filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"A crystal filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"A cavity filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"A DSP filter"}],"questionText":"Which type of filter would be best to use in a2-metre repeater duplexer?"},{"questionId":"A-005-006-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"pre-emphasis"},{"letter":"B","text":"the centre frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"de-emphasis"},{"letter":"D","text":"frequency inversion"}],"questionText":"The characteristic difference between aphase modulator and a frequency modulatoris:"},{"questionId":"A-005-006-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"between the modulator and the oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"in the microphone circuit, before theaudio amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"between the audio amplifier and themodulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"between the multiplier and the PA"}],"questionText":"In most modern FM transmitters, to producea better sound, a compressor and a clipperare placed:"},{"questionId":"A-005-006-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"modulation, pre-emphasis and carriersuppression"},{"letter":"B","text":"frequency stability, de-emphasis andlinearity"},{"letter":"C","text":"power, frequency deviation and frequencystability"},{"letter":"D","text":"distortion, bandwidth and sideband power"}],"questionText":"Three important parameters to be verified inan FM transmitter are:"},{"questionId":"A-005-006-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"passive intermodulation"},{"letter":"B","text":"intermediate frequency stage"},{"letter":"C","text":"final amplifier stage"},{"letter":"D","text":"receiver frontend"}],"questionText":"Intermodulation interference products are nottypically associated with which of thefollowing:"},{"questionId":"A-005-007-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a lower signal-to-noise ratio"},{"letter":"B","text":"circuit level instability"},{"letter":"C","text":"full amplification of low level signals andreducing or eliminating amplification ofhigh level signals"},{"letter":"D","text":"full amplification of high level signals andreducing or eliminating signalsamplification of low level"}],"questionText":"Speech compression associated with SSBtransmission implies:"},{"questionId":"A-005-007-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Aliasing amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"Analog to digital converter"},{"letter":"C","text":"Digital to analog converter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Mathematical transform"}],"questionText":"Which of the following functions is notincluded in a typical digital signalprocessor?"},{"questionId":"A-005-007-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"16 bits"},{"letter":"B","text":"4 bits"},{"letter":"C","text":"8 bits"},{"letter":"D","text":"6 bits"}],"questionText":"How many bits are required to provide 256discrete levels, or a ratio of 256:1?"},{"questionId":"A-005-007-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"6 dB"},{"letter":"B","text":"1 dB"},{"letter":"C","text":"4 dB"},{"letter":"D","text":"3 dB"}],"questionText":"Adding one bit to the word length, isequivalent to adding ____ dB to the dynamicrange of the digitizer:"},{"questionId":"A-005-007-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Digital formatter"},{"letter":"B","text":"Mathematical transformer"},{"letter":"C","text":"Digital transformer"},{"letter":"D","text":"Digital signal processor"}],"questionText":"What do you call the circuit which employsan analog to digital converter, amathematical transform, a digital to analogconverter and a low pass filter?"},{"questionId":"A-005-007-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Frequency division"},{"letter":"B","text":"Compression"},{"letter":"C","text":"Bandwidth limiting"},{"letter":"D","text":"Clipping"}],"questionText":"Which principle is not associated withanalog signal processing?"},{"questionId":"A-005-007-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"AF clipping"},{"letter":"B","text":"Frequency clipping"},{"letter":"C","text":"RF clipping"},{"letter":"D","text":"Compression"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is not a method usedfor peak limiting, in a signal processor?"},{"questionId":"A-005-007-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Increased harmonic distortion"},{"letter":"B","text":"Reduced average power"},{"letter":"C","text":"Increased average power"},{"letter":"D","text":"Reduction in peak amplitude"}],"questionText":"What is the undesirable result of AF clippingin a speech processor?"},{"questionId":"A-005-007-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"has less distortion"},{"letter":"B","text":"is more expensive to implement"},{"letter":"C","text":"is more difficult to implement"},{"letter":"D","text":"is easier to implement"}],"questionText":"Which description is not correct? You areplanning to build a speech processor foryour transceiver. Compared to AF clipping,RF clipping:"},{"questionId":"A-005-008-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Baudot"},{"letter":"B","text":"ASCII"},{"letter":"C","text":"Varicode"},{"letter":"D","text":"AX.25"}],"questionText":"What digital code consists of elementshaving unequal length?"},{"questionId":"A-005-008-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The transport layer"},{"letter":"B","text":"The physical layer"},{"letter":"C","text":"The link layer"},{"letter":"D","text":"The network layer"}],"questionText":"Open Systems Interconnection (OSI) modelstandardizes communications functions aslayers within a data communicationssystem. Amateur digital radio systemsoften follow the OSI model in structure.What is the base layer of the OSI modelinvolving the interconnection of a packetradio TNC to a computer terminal?"},{"questionId":"A-005-008-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Lossless compression"},{"letter":"B","text":"Error detection"},{"letter":"C","text":"Lossy compression"},{"letter":"D","text":"Error correction"}],"questionText":"What is the purpose of a Cyclic RedundancyCheck (CRC)?"},{"questionId":"A-005-008-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"ASCII characters contain fewerinformation bits"},{"letter":"B","text":"The larger character set allows store-and-forward"},{"letter":"C","text":"It includes both upper and lower casetext characters in the code"},{"letter":"D","text":"ASCII includes built-in error correction"}],"questionText":"What is one advantage of using ASCII ratherthan Baudot code?"},{"questionId":"A-005-008-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Mode A AMTOR does not include anerror control system"},{"letter":"B","text":"The receiving station automaticallyrequests repeats when needed"},{"letter":"C","text":"The receiving station checks the framecheck sequence (FCS) against thetransmitted FCS"},{"letter":"D","text":"Each character is sent twice"}],"questionText":"What type of error control system is used inAMTOR ARQ (Mode A)?"},{"questionId":"A-005-008-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Each character is sent twice"},{"letter":"B","text":"Mode B AMTOR does not include anerror-correction system"},{"letter":"C","text":"The receiving station automaticallyrequests repeats when needed"},{"letter":"D","text":"The receiving station checks the framecheck sequence (FCS) against thetransmitted FCS"}],"questionText":"What error-correction system is used inAMTOR FEC (Mode B)?"},{"questionId":"A-005-008-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Automatic link establishment"},{"letter":"B","text":"Two-way messaging"},{"letter":"C","text":"Telemetry"},{"letter":"D","text":"Amateur-specific local informationbroadcast"}],"questionText":"APRS (Automatic Packet ReportingSystem) does NOT support which one ofthese functions?"},{"questionId":"A-005-008-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Convolution code"},{"letter":"B","text":"Lempel-Ziv routine"},{"letter":"C","text":"Hash function"},{"letter":"D","text":"Dynamic Huffman code"}],"questionText":"Which algorithm may be used to create aCyclic Redundancy Check (CRC)?"},{"questionId":"A-005-008-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"5"},{"letter":"B","text":"7"},{"letter":"C","text":"8"},{"letter":"D","text":"6"}],"questionText":"How many information bits are included inthe Baudot code?"},{"questionId":"A-005-008-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"6"},{"letter":"B","text":"5"},{"letter":"C","text":"8"},{"letter":"D","text":"7"}],"questionText":"How many information bits are included inthe ISO-8859 extension to the ASCII code?"},{"questionId":"A-005-009-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"AMTOR"},{"letter":"B","text":"Time domain frequency modulation"},{"letter":"C","text":"Spread spectrum communication"},{"letter":"D","text":"Amplitude-companded single sideband"}],"questionText":"What term describes a wide-bandcommunications system in which the RFcarrier varies according to somepredetermined sequence?"},{"questionId":"A-005-009-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Frequency companded spread spectrum"},{"letter":"B","text":"Frequency hopping"},{"letter":"C","text":"Direct sequence"},{"letter":"D","text":"Time-domain frequency modulation"}],"questionText":"What is the term used to describe a spreadspectrum communications system wherethe centre frequency of a conventional carrieris changed many times per second inaccordance with a pseudorandom list ofchannels?"},{"questionId":"A-005-009-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Direct sequence"},{"letter":"B","text":"Frequency hopping"},{"letter":"C","text":"Phase companded spread spectrum"},{"letter":"D","text":"Binary phase-shift keying"}],"questionText":"What term is used to describe a spreadspectrum communications system in whicha very fast binary bit stream is used to shiftthe phase of an RF carrier?"},{"questionId":"A-005-009-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"RTTY"},{"letter":"B","text":"Spread spectrum"},{"letter":"C","text":"AMTOR"},{"letter":"D","text":"Packet"}],"questionText":"Frequency hopping is used with which typeof transmission?"},{"questionId":"A-005-009-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"RTTY"},{"letter":"B","text":"Spread spectrum"},{"letter":"C","text":"AMTOR"},{"letter":"D","text":"Packet"}],"questionText":"Direct sequence is used with which type oftransmission?"},{"questionId":"A-005-009-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Quantizing noise"},{"letter":"B","text":"Random noise sequence"},{"letter":"C","text":"Pseudo-random sequence"},{"letter":"D","text":"Frequency-companded sequence"}],"questionText":"Which type of signal is used to produce apredetermined alteration in the carrier forspread spectrum communication?"},{"questionId":"A-005-009-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It varies too quickly in amplitude"},{"letter":"B","text":"The signal is too distorted for comfortablelistening"},{"letter":"C","text":"Your receiver must be frequency-synchronized to the transmitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"It requires narrower bandwidth than mostreceivers have"}],"questionText":"Why is it difficult to monitor a spreadspectrum transmission?"},{"questionId":"A-005-009-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The carrier is phase-shifted by a fastbinary bit stream"},{"letter":"B","text":"The carrier is amplitude modulated over arange called the spread"},{"letter":"C","text":"The carrier is frequency-companded"},{"letter":"D","text":"The carrier is altered in accordance witha pseudo-random list of channels"}],"questionText":"What is direct-sequence spread spectrum?"},{"questionId":"A-005-009-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"If interference is detected by the receiver,it will signal the transmitter to changefrequencies"},{"letter":"B","text":"The high power used by a spread-spectrum transmitter keeps its signalfrom being easily overpowered"},{"letter":"C","text":"Signals not using the spectrum-spreadingalgorithm are suppressed in the receiver"},{"letter":"D","text":"The receiver is always equipped with aspecial digital signal processor (DSP)interference filter"}],"questionText":"Why are received spread-spectrum signalsso resistant to interference?"},{"questionId":"A-005-009-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The frequency of an RF carrier ischanged very rapidly according to aparticular pseudo-random sequence"},{"letter":"B","text":"If interference is detected by the receiver,it will signal the transmitter to changefrequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"If interference is detected by the receiver,it will signal the transmitter to wait untilthe frequency is clear"},{"letter":"D","text":"A pseudo-random bit stream is used toshift the phase of an RF carrier veryrapidly in a particular sequence"}],"questionText":"How does the spread-spectrum technique offrequency hopping work?"},{"questionId":"A-006-001-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Automatic squelching and increasedsensitivity"},{"letter":"B","text":"Increased selectivity and optimal tunedcircuit design"},{"letter":"C","text":"Automatic detection in the RF amplifierand increased sensitivity"},{"letter":"D","text":"Automatic soft-limiting and automaticsquelching"}],"questionText":"What are the advantages of the frequencyconversion process in a superheterodynereceiver?"},{"questionId":"A-006-001-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Interference to other services"},{"letter":"B","text":"Cross-modulation distortion andinterference"},{"letter":"C","text":"Image rejection and responses tounwanted signals"},{"letter":"D","text":"Noise figure and distortion"}],"questionText":"What factors should be considered whenselecting an intermediate frequency?"},{"questionId":"A-006-001-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"is much more sensitive"},{"letter":"B","text":"produces a louder signal at the output"},{"letter":"C","text":"greater reduction of image interference fora given front end selectivity"},{"letter":"D","text":"is much more stable"}],"questionText":"One of the greatest advantages of thedouble-conversion over the single-conversionreceiver is that it:"},{"questionId":"A-006-001-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"detector"},{"letter":"B","text":"IF circuits"},{"letter":"C","text":"local oscillator"},{"letter":"D","text":"audio output stage"}],"questionText":"In a communications receiver, a crystal filterwould be located in the:"},{"questionId":"A-006-001-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"poorer selectivity in the IF caused by themultitude of frequency changes"},{"letter":"B","text":"greater sensitivity introducing higherlevels of RF to the receiver"},{"letter":"C","text":"AGC being forced to work harder causingthe stages concerned to overload"},{"letter":"D","text":"additional oscillators and mixingfrequencies involved in the design"}],"questionText":"A multiple conversion superheterodynereceiver is more susceptible to spuriousresponses than a single-conversion receiverbecause of the:"},{"questionId":"A-006-001-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The local oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"The audio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"The detector"},{"letter":"D","text":"The RF amplifier"}],"questionText":"Which stage of a receiver has its input andoutput circuits tuned to the receivedfrequency?"},{"questionId":"A-006-001-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Mixer"},{"letter":"B","text":"Radio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"Intermediate frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"Local oscillator"}],"questionText":"Which stage of a superheterodyne receiverlies between a tuneable stage and a fixedtuned stage?"},{"questionId":"A-006-001-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"16 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"21 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"9 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"7 MHz"}],"questionText":"A single conversion receiver with a 9 MHz IFhas a local oscillator operating at 16 MHz.The frequency it is tuned to is:"},{"questionId":"A-006-001-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"two IF stages and one local oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"two IF stages and two local oscillators"},{"letter":"C","text":"one IF stage and one local oscillator"},{"letter":"D","text":"two IF stages and three local oscillators"}],"questionText":"A double conversion receiver designed forSSB reception has a beat frequencyoscillator and:"},{"questionId":"A-006-001-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"does not drift off frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"is a more sensitive receiver"},{"letter":"C","text":"produces a louder audio signal"},{"letter":"D","text":"suffers less from image interference for agiven front end sensitivity"}],"questionText":"The advantage of a double conversionreceiver over a single conversion receiver isthat it:"},{"questionId":"A-006-002-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"allow a number of IF frequencies to beused"},{"letter":"B","text":"remove image signals from the receiver"},{"letter":"C","text":"produce an audio frequency for thespeaker"},{"letter":"D","text":"change the frequency of the incomingsignal to that of the IF"}],"questionText":"The mixer stage of a superheterodynereceiver is used to:"},{"questionId":"A-006-002-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"it reduces the pass-band of the IF stages"},{"letter":"B","text":"it beats with the receiver carrier toproduce the missing sideband"},{"letter":"C","text":"the suppressed carrier must be replacedfor detection"},{"letter":"D","text":"it phases out the unwanted sidebandsignal"}],"questionText":"A superheterodyne receiver designed forSSB reception must have a beat-frequencyoscillator (BFO) because:"},{"questionId":"A-006-002-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a radio frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"a high frequency oscillator (HFO)frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"an intermediate frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"an audio frequency"}],"questionText":"The first mixer in the receiver mixes theincoming signal with the local oscillator toproduce:"},{"questionId":"A-006-002-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"to protect the incoming signal frominterference"},{"letter":"B","text":"to beat with the incoming signal"},{"letter":"C","text":"to pass the signal without interruption"},{"letter":"D","text":"to provide additional amplification"}],"questionText":"The BFO is off-set slightly (500 - 1 500 Hz)from the incoming signal to the detector.This is required:"},{"questionId":"A-006-002-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"stable and sensitive"},{"letter":"B","text":"selective and spectrally pure"},{"letter":"C","text":"stable and spectrally pure"},{"letter":"D","text":"sensitive and selective"}],"questionText":"It is very important that the oscillatorscontained in a superheterodyne receiver are:"},{"questionId":"A-006-002-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"tuning of the local oscillator (LO)"},{"letter":"B","text":"tuning both the antenna and the BFO"},{"letter":"C","text":"tuning of the beat-frequency oscillator(BFO)"},{"letter":"D","text":"tuning both the antenna and the LO"}],"questionText":"In a superheterodyne receiver, a stagebefore the IF amplifier has a variablecapacitor in parallel with a trimmer capacitorand an inductance. The variable capacitor isfor:"},{"questionId":"A-006-002-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"tuning the beat-frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"tuning both the antenna and the localoscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"tuning the receiver preselector to thereception frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"tuning both the antenna and the beat-frequency oscillator"}],"questionText":"In a superheterodyne receiver without an RFamplifier, the input to the mixer stage has avariable capacitor in parallel with aninductance. The variable capacitor is for:"},{"questionId":"A-006-002-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"BFO"},{"letter":"B","text":"VFO"},{"letter":"C","text":"Multiplier"},{"letter":"D","text":"Mixer"}],"questionText":"What receiver stage combines a 14.25-MHzinput signal with a 13.795-MHz oscillatorsignal to produce a 455-kHz intermediatefrequency (IF) signal?"},{"questionId":"A-006-002-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"IF and local oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"RF and IF"},{"letter":"C","text":"RF and local oscillator"},{"letter":"D","text":"RF and first mixer"}],"questionText":"Which two stages in a superheterodynereceiver have input tuned circuits tuned tothe same frequency?"},{"questionId":"A-006-002-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"produces an intermediate frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"produces spurious signals"},{"letter":"C","text":"acts as a buffer stage"},{"letter":"D","text":"demodulates SSB signals"}],"questionText":"The mixer stage of a superheterodynereceiver:"},{"questionId":"A-006-003-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The weakest signal that can be detectedabove the receiver internal noise"},{"letter":"B","text":"The weakest signal that can be detectedunder noisy atmospheric conditions"},{"letter":"C","text":"The minimum level of noise that willoverload the receiver RF amplifier stage"},{"letter":"D","text":"The amount of noise generated by thereceiver local oscillator"}],"questionText":"What is meant by the noise floor of areceiver?"},{"questionId":"A-006-003-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Sufficient gain to keep weak signalsbelow the noise of the first mixer stage"},{"letter":"B","text":"Sufficient gain to allow weak signals toovercome noise generated in the firstmixer stage"},{"letter":"C","text":"As much gain as possible, short of self-oscillation"},{"letter":"D","text":"It depends on the amplification factor ofthe first IF stage"}],"questionText":"How much gain should be used in the RFamplifier stage of a receiver?"},{"questionId":"A-006-003-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To provide most of the receiver gain"},{"letter":"B","text":"To improve the receiver noise figure"},{"letter":"C","text":"To vary the receiver image rejection byusing the AGC"},{"letter":"D","text":"To develop the AGC voltage"}],"questionText":"What is the primary purpose of an RFamplifier in a receiver?"},{"questionId":"A-006-003-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Noise Figure in decibels"},{"letter":"B","text":"Overall gain in decibels"},{"letter":"C","text":"RF level for 12 dB SINAD"},{"letter":"D","text":"RF level for a given Bit Error Rate (BER)"}],"questionText":"How is receiver sensitivity often expressedfor UHF FM receivers?"},{"questionId":"A-006-003-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Stability"},{"letter":"B","text":"Noise figure"},{"letter":"C","text":"Dynamic range"},{"letter":"D","text":"Design parameter"}],"questionText":"What is the term used for the decibeldifference (or ratio) between the largesttolerable receiver input signal (withoutcausing audible distortion products) and theminimum discernible signal (sensitivity)?"},{"questionId":"A-006-003-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"rejection of unwanted signals"},{"letter":"B","text":"selectivity"},{"letter":"C","text":"stability"},{"letter":"D","text":"sensitivity"}],"questionText":"The lower the receiver noise figure becomes,the greater will be the receiver's _________:"},{"questionId":"A-006-003-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"detector and AF amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"BFO and detector"},{"letter":"C","text":"IF amplifier and detector"},{"letter":"D","text":"RF amplifier and mixer"}],"questionText":"The noise generated in a receiver of gooddesign originates in the:"},{"questionId":"A-006-003-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Ionospheric distortion of the receivedsignal creates high noise levels"},{"letter":"B","text":"The use of SSB and CW on the HFbands overcomes the noise"},{"letter":"C","text":"Regardless of the front end, thesucceeding stages when used on HF arevery noisy"},{"letter":"D","text":"External HF noise, man-made andnatural, are higher than the internal noisegenerated by the receiver"}],"questionText":"Why are very low noise figures relativelyunimportant for a high frequency receiver?"},{"questionId":"A-006-003-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"dynamic range"},{"letter":"B","text":"AGC"},{"letter":"C","text":"cross-modulation index"},{"letter":"D","text":"noise figure"}],"questionText":"The term which relates specifically to theamplitude levels of multiple signals that canbe accommodated during reception iscalled:"},{"questionId":"A-006-003-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"preselector"},{"letter":"B","text":"preamble"},{"letter":"C","text":"preamplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"pass-selector"}],"questionText":"Normally, front-end selectivity is provided bythe resonant networks both before and afterthe RF stage in a superheterodyne receiver.This whole section of the receiver is oftenreferred to as the:"},{"questionId":"A-006-004-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It detects cross-modulation products"},{"letter":"B","text":"It mixes an incoming signal with a locallygenerated carrier"},{"letter":"C","text":"It provides local oscillations for input to amixer"},{"letter":"D","text":"It amplifies and narrows band-passfrequencies"}],"questionText":"What does a product detector do?"},{"questionId":"A-006-004-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"AF amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"RF amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"automatic gain control (AGC)"},{"letter":"D","text":"IF amplifier"}],"questionText":"Distortion in a receiver that only affectsstrong signals usually indicates a defect inor mis-adjustment of the:"},{"questionId":"A-006-004-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"distorts the signal"},{"letter":"B","text":"introduces limiting"},{"letter":"C","text":"reduces the receiver gain"},{"letter":"D","text":"increases the receiver gain"}],"questionText":"In a superheterodyne receiver with automaticgain control (AGC), as the strength of thesignal increases, the AGC:"},{"questionId":"A-006-004-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"LO"},{"letter":"B","text":"detector"},{"letter":"C","text":"RF amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"audio output"}],"questionText":"The amplified IF signal is applied to the____________ stage in a superheterodynereceiver:"},{"questionId":"A-006-004-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"fed directly to the speaker"},{"letter":"B","text":"applied to the RF amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"applied to the AF amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"grounded via the chassis"}],"questionText":"The low-level output of a detector is:"},{"questionId":"A-006-004-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"inverse gain control"},{"letter":"B","text":"automatic load control"},{"letter":"C","text":"automatic gain control"},{"letter":"D","text":"automatic frequency control"}],"questionText":"The overall output of an AM/CW/SSBreceiver can be adjusted by means ofmanual controls on the receiver or by use ofa circuit known as:"},{"questionId":"A-006-004-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"RF and IF amplifiers"},{"letter":"B","text":"AF and IF amplifiers"},{"letter":"C","text":"RF and AF amplifiers"},{"letter":"D","text":"detector and AF amplifiers"}],"questionText":"AGC voltage is applied to the:"},{"questionId":"A-006-004-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"IF derived or RF derived"},{"letter":"B","text":"detector derived or audio derived"},{"letter":"C","text":"IF derived or audio derived"},{"letter":"D","text":"RF derived or audio derived"}],"questionText":"AGC is derived in a receiver from one of twocircuits. Depending on the method used, itis called:"},{"questionId":"A-006-004-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Slope and bandwidth"},{"letter":"B","text":"Clipping level and hang time"},{"letter":"C","text":"Threshold and decay time"},{"letter":"D","text":"Blanking level and slope"}],"questionText":"Which two variables primarily determine thebehaviour of an automatic gain control (AGC)loop?"},{"questionId":"A-006-005-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"AGC loop"},{"letter":"B","text":"IF filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"RF amplifier pre-selector"},{"letter":"D","text":"Product detector"}],"questionText":"What part of a superheterodyne receiverdetermines the image rejection ratio of thereceiver?"},{"questionId":"A-006-005-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Desensitization"},{"letter":"B","text":"Cross-modulation interference"},{"letter":"C","text":"Squelch gain rollback"},{"letter":"D","text":"Quieting"}],"questionText":"What is the term for the reduction in receiversensitivity caused by a strong signal nearthe received frequency?"},{"questionId":"A-006-005-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Audio gain adjusted too low"},{"letter":"B","text":"Strong near frequency signals"},{"letter":"C","text":"Squelch gain adjusted too high"},{"letter":"D","text":"Squelch gain adjusted too low"}],"questionText":"What causes receiver desensitization?"},{"questionId":"A-006-005-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Increase the receiver bandwidth"},{"letter":"B","text":"Increase the transmitter audio gain"},{"letter":"C","text":"Use a cavity filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Decrease the receiver squelch gain"}],"questionText":"What is one way receiver desensitizationcan be reduced?"},{"questionId":"A-006-005-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Positive feedback"},{"letter":"B","text":"Lack of neutralization"},{"letter":"C","text":"Nonlinear circuits or devices"},{"letter":"D","text":"Too little gain"}],"questionText":"What causes intermodulation in anelectronic circuit?"},{"questionId":"A-006-005-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To move the image response far awayfrom the filter passband"},{"letter":"B","text":"To provide a greater tuning range"},{"letter":"C","text":"To tune out cross-modulation distortion"},{"letter":"D","text":"To prevent the generation of spuriousmixer products"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is an importantreason for using a VHF intermediatefrequency in an HF receiver?"},{"questionId":"A-006-005-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the interaction of products from high-powered transmitters in the area"},{"letter":"B","text":"the high-voltage stages in the finalamplifier of an amplitude or frequency-modulated transmitter"},{"letter":"C","text":"the mixing of more than one signal in thefirst or second intermediate frequencyamplifiers of a receiver"},{"letter":"D","text":"the mixing of two or more signals in thefront-end of a superheterodyne receiver"}],"questionText":"Intermodulation interference is produced by:"},{"questionId":"A-006-005-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Temperature variations"},{"letter":"B","text":"Dial display accuracy"},{"letter":"C","text":"Mechanical rigidity"},{"letter":"D","text":"Feedback components"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is NOT a direct causeof instability in a receiver?"},{"questionId":"A-006-005-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"RF amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"mixer"},{"letter":"C","text":"local oscillator and power supply"},{"letter":"D","text":"detector"}],"questionText":"Poor frequency stability in a receiver usuallyoriginates in the:"},{"questionId":"A-006-005-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Two-tone Third-Order IMD DynamicRange, 10 MHz spacing"},{"letter":"B","text":"Third-Order Intercept Point"},{"letter":"C","text":"Blocking Dynamic Range"},{"letter":"D","text":"Intermediate frequency rejection ratio"}],"questionText":"Which of these measurements is a goodindicator of VHF receiver performance in anenvironment of strong out-of-band signals?"},{"questionId":"A-007-001-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The circuit is known as a transformer-type antenna tuner"},{"letter":"B","text":"The circuit is known as a Pi-type antennatuner"},{"letter":"C","text":"The input is suitable for 50 ohmimpedance"},{"letter":"D","text":"The output is suitable for impedancesfrom low to high"}],"questionText":"For an antenna tuner of the \"Transformer\"type, which of the following statements isFALSE?"},{"questionId":"A-007-001-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The input is suitable for impedance of 50ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"The circuit is known as a Pi-type antennatuner"},{"letter":"C","text":"The circuit is known as a Series-typeantenna tuner"},{"letter":"D","text":"The output is suitable for impedancesfrom low to high"}],"questionText":"For an antenna tuner of the \"Series\" type,which of the following statements is false?"},{"questionId":"A-007-001-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The antenna output is high impedance"},{"letter":"B","text":"The circuit is known as an L-typeantenna tuner"},{"letter":"C","text":"The circuit is suitable for matching to avertical ground plane antenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"The transmitter input is suitable for 50ohms impedance"}],"questionText":"For an antenna tuner of the \"L\" type, whichof the following statements is false?"},{"questionId":"A-007-001-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The circuit is a Pi-type antenna tuner"},{"letter":"B","text":"The circuit is a series-type antenna tuner"},{"letter":"C","text":"The transmitter input is suitable forimpedance of 50 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"The antenna output is suitable forimpedances from low to high"}],"questionText":"For an antenna tuner of the \"Pi\" type, whichof the following statements is false?"},{"questionId":"A-007-001-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A network consisting of one inductor andtwo capacitors or two inductors and onecapacitor"},{"letter":"B","text":"An antenna matching network that isisolated from ground"},{"letter":"C","text":"A network consisting of four inductors orfour capacitors"},{"letter":"D","text":"A power incidence network"}],"questionText":"What is a pi-network?"},{"questionId":"A-007-001-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Butterworth"},{"letter":"B","text":"L-network"},{"letter":"C","text":"Pi-network"},{"letter":"D","text":"Chebyshev"}],"questionText":"Which type of network offers the greatesttransformation ratio?"},{"questionId":"A-007-001-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It has limited power handling capability"},{"letter":"B","text":"It matches only a small impedance range"},{"letter":"C","text":"It is thermally unstable"},{"letter":"D","text":"It is prone to self-resonance"}],"questionText":"Why is an L-network of limited utility inimpedance matching?"},{"questionId":"A-007-001-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Greater transformation range"},{"letter":"B","text":"Greater harmonic suppression"},{"letter":"C","text":"Higher efficiency"},{"letter":"D","text":"Lower losses"}],"questionText":"What advantage does a pi-L network haveover a pi-network for impedance matchingbetween a vacuum tube linear amplifier anda multiband antenna?"},{"questionId":"A-007-001-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"L-network"},{"letter":"B","text":"Pi-L network"},{"letter":"C","text":"Inverse pi-network"},{"letter":"D","text":"Pi-network"}],"questionText":"Which type of network provides the greatestharmonic suppression?"},{"questionId":"A-007-001-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"because it simplifies mathematicaloperations"},{"letter":"B","text":"only to solve matching and transmissionline problems"},{"letter":"C","text":"to solve problems in direct currentcircuits"},{"letter":"D","text":"because it only works with complexnumbers"}],"questionText":"A Smith Chart is useful:"},{"questionId":"A-007-002-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The same as the output impedance of thesource"},{"letter":"B","text":"A very low impedance"},{"letter":"C","text":"A very high impedance"},{"letter":"D","text":"The same as the characteristicimpedance of the transmission line"}],"questionText":"What kind of impedance does a quarterwavelength transmission line present to thesource when the line is shorted at the farend?"},{"questionId":"A-007-002-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A very high impedance"},{"letter":"B","text":"The same as the output impedance of thesource"},{"letter":"C","text":"The same as the characteristicimpedance of the transmission line"},{"letter":"D","text":"A very low impedance"}],"questionText":"What kind of impedance does a quarterwavelength transmission line present to thesource if the line is open at the far end?"},{"questionId":"A-007-002-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A very low impedance"},{"letter":"B","text":"A very high impedance"},{"letter":"C","text":"The same as the characteristicimpedance of the transmission line"},{"letter":"D","text":"The same as the output impedance of thesource"}],"questionText":"What kind of impedance does a halfwavelength transmission line present to thesource when the line is open at the far end?"},{"questionId":"A-007-002-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A very high impedance"},{"letter":"B","text":"The same as the characteristicimpedance of the transmission line"},{"letter":"C","text":"The same as the output impedance of thesource"},{"letter":"D","text":"A very low impedance"}],"questionText":"What kind of impedance does a halfwavelength transmission line present to thesource when the line is shorted at the farend?"},{"questionId":"A-007-002-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Surge impedance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Standing wave ratio"},{"letter":"C","text":"Velocity factor"},{"letter":"D","text":"Characteristic impedance"}],"questionText":"What is the term for the ratio of the actualvelocity at which a signal travels through atransmission line to the speed of light in avacuum?"},{"questionId":"A-007-002-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2.7"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.66"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.33"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.1"}],"questionText":"What is a typical velocity factor for coaxialcable with polyethylene dielectric?"},{"questionId":"A-007-002-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The line length"},{"letter":"B","text":"The centre conductor resistivity"},{"letter":"C","text":"The terminal impedance"},{"letter":"D","text":"Dielectrics in the line"}],"questionText":"What determines the velocity factor in atransmission line?"},{"questionId":"A-007-002-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Skin effect is less pronounced in thecoaxial cable"},{"letter":"B","text":"The characteristic impedance is higher ina parallel transmission line"},{"letter":"C","text":"RF energy moves slower along thecoaxial cable than in air"},{"letter":"D","text":"The surge impedance is higher in theparallel transmission line"}],"questionText":"Why is the physical length of a coaxialcable shorter than its electrical length?"},{"questionId":"A-007-002-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"impedance"},{"letter":"B","text":"hermetic losses"},{"letter":"C","text":"velocity factor"},{"letter":"D","text":"VSWR"}],"questionText":"The reciprocal of the square root of thedielectric constant of the material used toseparate the conductors in a transmissionline gives the ____________ of the line:"},{"questionId":"A-007-002-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"ratio of the velocity of propagation in thetransmission line to the velocity ofpropagation in free space"},{"letter":"B","text":"impedance of the line, e.g. 50 ohm, 75ohm, etc."},{"letter":"C","text":"speed at which the signal travels in freespace"},{"letter":"D","text":"speed to which the standing waves arereflected back to the transmitter"}],"questionText":"The velocity factor of a transmission line isthe:"},{"questionId":"A-007-003-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The omega match"},{"letter":"B","text":"The stub match"},{"letter":"C","text":"The T match"},{"letter":"D","text":"The gamma match"}],"questionText":"What term describes a method used tomatch a high-impedance transmission lineto a lower impedance antenna by connectingthe line to the driven element in two places,spaced a fraction of a wavelength on eachside of the driven element centre?"},{"questionId":"A-007-003-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The T match"},{"letter":"B","text":"The gamma match"},{"letter":"C","text":"The omega match"},{"letter":"D","text":"The stub match"}],"questionText":"What term describes an unbalanced feedsystem in which the driven element of anantenna is fed both at the centre and afraction of a wavelength to one side ofcentre?"},{"questionId":"A-007-003-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3.51 metres (11.5 feet)"},{"letter":"B","text":"20 metres (65.6 feet)"},{"letter":"C","text":"2.33 metres (7.64 feet)"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.25 metre (0.82 foot)"}],"questionText":"Assuming a velocity factor of 0.66 whatwould be the physical length of a typicalcoaxial stub that is electrically one quarterwavelength long at 14.1 MHz?"},{"questionId":"A-007-003-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"gamma match"},{"letter":"B","text":"lambda match"},{"letter":"C","text":"T match"},{"letter":"D","text":"zeta match"}],"questionText":"The driven element of a Yagi antenna isconnected to a coaxial transmission line.The coax braid is connected to the centre ofthe driven element and the centre conductoris connected to a variable capacitor in serieswith an adjustable mechanical arrangementon one side of the driven element. The typeof matching is:"},{"questionId":"A-007-003-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"7.5 m (24.6 ft)"},{"letter":"B","text":"4 m (13.1 ft)"},{"letter":"C","text":"12 m (39.4 ft)"},{"letter":"D","text":"8 m (26.2 ft)"}],"questionText":"A quarter-wave stub, for use at 15 MHz, ismade from a coaxial cable having a velocityfactor of 0.8. Its physical length will be:"},{"questionId":"A-007-003-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"an \"omega\" match"},{"letter":"B","text":"a \"Y\" match"},{"letter":"C","text":"a \"gamma\" match"},{"letter":"D","text":"a \"T\" match"}],"questionText":"The matching of a driven element with asingle adjustable mechanical and capacitivearrangement is descriptive of:"},{"questionId":"A-007-003-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the adjustable gamma rod"},{"letter":"B","text":"the centre of the reflector"},{"letter":"C","text":"the centre of the driven element"},{"letter":"D","text":"the variable capacitor"}],"questionText":"A Yagi antenna uses a gamma match. Thecoaxial braid connects to:"},{"questionId":"A-007-003-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the coaxial line braid"},{"letter":"B","text":"the coaxial line centre conductor"},{"letter":"C","text":"the adjustable gamma rod"},{"letter":"D","text":"a variable capacitor"}],"questionText":"A Yagi antenna uses a gamma match. Thecentre of the driven element connects to:"},{"questionId":"A-007-003-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the variable capacitor"},{"letter":"B","text":"the coaxial line centre conductor"},{"letter":"C","text":"an adjustable point on the reflector"},{"letter":"D","text":"the centre of the driven element"}],"questionText":"A Yagi antenna uses a gamma match. Theadjustable gamma rod connects to:"},{"questionId":"A-007-003-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"an adjustable point on the director"},{"letter":"B","text":"center of the driven element"},{"letter":"C","text":"coaxial line braid"},{"letter":"D","text":"adjustable gamma rod"}],"questionText":"A Yagi antenna uses a gamma match. Thevariable capacitor connects to the:"},{"questionId":"A-007-004-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"current"},{"letter":"B","text":"inductance"},{"letter":"C","text":"capacitance"},{"letter":"D","text":"voltage"}],"questionText":"In a half-wave dipole, the distribution of_______ is highest at each end."},{"questionId":"A-007-004-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"current"},{"letter":"B","text":"voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"inductance"},{"letter":"D","text":"capacitance"}],"questionText":"In a half-wave dipole, the distribution of_______ is lowest at each end."},{"questionId":"A-007-004-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"current"},{"letter":"B","text":"voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"capacity"},{"letter":"D","text":"inductance"}],"questionText":"In a half-wave dipole, the lowest distributionof _________ occurs at the middle."},{"questionId":"A-007-004-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"inductance"},{"letter":"B","text":"voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"capacity"},{"letter":"D","text":"current"}],"questionText":"In a half-wave dipole, the highest distributionof ________ occurs at the middle."},{"questionId":"A-007-004-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the resistance is maximum"},{"letter":"B","text":"the antenna is resonant"},{"letter":"C","text":"the current is maximum"},{"letter":"D","text":"the voltage is maximum"}],"questionText":"A half-wave dipole antenna is normally fed atthe point where:"},{"questionId":"A-007-004-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"voltage is low and current is high"},{"letter":"B","text":"voltage is high and current is low"},{"letter":"C","text":"voltage and current are both high"},{"letter":"D","text":"voltage and current are both low"}],"questionText":"At the ends of a half-wave dipole:"},{"questionId":"A-007-004-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"voltage and current are both high"},{"letter":"B","text":"voltage and current are both low"},{"letter":"C","text":"voltage is high and current is low"},{"letter":"D","text":"voltage is low and current is high"}],"questionText":"The impedance of a half-wave antenna at itscentre is low, because at this point:"},{"questionId":"A-007-004-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It is equal at all points"},{"letter":"B","text":"Both ends"},{"letter":"C","text":"The centre"},{"letter":"D","text":"At the right end"}],"questionText":"In a half-wave dipole, where does minimumvoltage occur?"},{"questionId":"A-007-004-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It is equal at all points"},{"letter":"B","text":"At the right end"},{"letter":"C","text":"At both ends"},{"letter":"D","text":"At the centre"}],"questionText":"In a half-wave dipole, where does theminimum current occur?"},{"questionId":"A-007-004-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It is the same at all points"},{"letter":"B","text":"At the right end"},{"letter":"C","text":"At both ends"},{"letter":"D","text":"At the centre"}],"questionText":"In a half-wave dipole, where does theminimum impedance occur?"},{"questionId":"A-007-005-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Waves with a rotating electric field"},{"letter":"B","text":"Waves with an electric field bent intocircular shape"},{"letter":"C","text":"Waves that circle the earth"},{"letter":"D","text":"Waves produced by a circular loopantenna"}],"questionText":"What is meant by circularly polarizedelectromagnetic waves?"},{"questionId":"A-007-005-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Perpendicular polarization"},{"letter":"B","text":"None of the other answers, the two fieldscancel out"},{"letter":"C","text":"Circular polarization"},{"letter":"D","text":"Cross-polarization"}],"questionText":"What type of polarization is produced bycrossed dipoles fed 90 degrees out ofphase?"},{"questionId":"A-007-005-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Contact through a hilltop repeater"},{"letter":"B","text":"Simplex line-of-sight contact betweenhand-held transceivers"},{"letter":"C","text":"Contact with terrestrial mobile stations"},{"letter":"D","text":"Contact via satellite"}],"questionText":"On VHF/UHF frequencies, Doppler shiftbecomes of consequence on which type ofcommunication?"},{"questionId":"A-007-005-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"20 dB or more"},{"letter":"B","text":"3 dB"},{"letter":"C","text":"6 dB"},{"letter":"D","text":"10 dB"}],"questionText":"For VHF and UHF signals over a fixed path,what extra loss can be expected whenlinearly-polarized antennas are crossed-polarized (90 degrees)?"},{"questionId":"A-007-005-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Cassegrain"},{"letter":"B","text":"Newtonian"},{"letter":"C","text":"Front feed"},{"letter":"D","text":"Offset feed"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is NOT a validparabolic dish illumination arrangement?"},{"questionId":"A-007-005-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a horn-type radiator can be used to trapthe received energy"},{"letter":"B","text":"all the received energy is focused to apoint where the pick-up antenna islocated"},{"letter":"C","text":"a dipole antenna can be used to pick upthe received energy"},{"letter":"D","text":"no impedance matching is required"}],"questionText":"A parabolic antenna is very efficientbecause:"},{"questionId":"A-007-005-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"left-hand polarization"},{"letter":"B","text":"vertical polarization only"},{"letter":"C","text":"horizontal polarization"},{"letter":"D","text":"right-hand polarization"}],"questionText":"A helical-beam antenna with right-handpolarization will best receive signals with:"},{"questionId":"A-007-005-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"helical-beam antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"folded dipole antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"ground-plane antenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"quad antenna"}],"questionText":"One antenna which will respondsimultaneously to vertically- andhorizontally-polarized signals is the:"},{"questionId":"A-007-005-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"5 mm (0.2 in) regardless of frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"1% of the diameter"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.1 lambda"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.25 lambda"}],"questionText":"In amateur work, what is the surface errorupper limit you should try not to exceed on aparabolic reflector?"},{"questionId":"A-007-005-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the focal length of the antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"the material composition of the dish"},{"letter":"C","text":"the diameter of the antenna inwavelengths"},{"letter":"D","text":"the polarization of the feed deviceilluminating it"}],"questionText":"You want to convert a surplus parabolic dishfor amateur radio use, the gain of thisantenna depends on:"},{"questionId":"A-007-006-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"350 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"400 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"300 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"200 watts"}],"questionText":"A transmitter has an output of 100 watts.The cable and connectors have a compositeloss of 3 dB, and the antenna has a gain of6 dBd. What is the Effective RadiatedPower?"},{"questionId":"A-007-006-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"197 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"228 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"178 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"390 watts"}],"questionText":"What is the Effective Radiated Power of anamateur transmitter, if the transmitter outputpower is 200 watts, the transmission lineloss is 5 watts, and the antenna power gainis 3 dBd?"},{"questionId":"A-007-006-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"power supplied to the transmission lineplus antenna gain"},{"letter":"B","text":"ratio of signal output power to signal inputpower"},{"letter":"C","text":"transmitter output power, minus linelosses, plus antenna gain relative to adipole"},{"letter":"D","text":"power supplied to the antenna before themodulation of the carrier"}],"questionText":"Effective Radiated Power means the:"},{"questionId":"A-007-006-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1600 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"400 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"800 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"3200 watts"}],"questionText":"A transmitter has an output power of 200watts. The coaxial and connector losses are3 dB in total, and the antenna gain is 9 dBd.What is the approximate Effective RadiatedPower of this system?"},{"questionId":"A-007-006-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"100 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"200 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"800 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"400 watts"}],"questionText":"A transmitter has a power output of 100watts. There is a loss of 1.30 dB in thetransmission line, a loss of 0.2 dB throughthe antenna tuner, and a gain of 4.50 dBd inthe antenna. The Effective Radiated Power(ERP) is:"},{"questionId":"A-007-006-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"remain the same"},{"letter":"B","text":"be cut in half"},{"letter":"C","text":"double"},{"letter":"D","text":"decrease by 3 watts"}],"questionText":"If the overall gain of an amateur station isincreased by 3 dB the ERP (EffectiveRadiated Power) will:"},{"questionId":"A-007-006-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1125"},{"letter":"B","text":"134"},{"letter":"C","text":"1000"},{"letter":"D","text":"1250"}],"questionText":"A transmitter has a power output of 125watts. There is a loss of 0.8 dB in thetransmission line, 0.2 dB in the antennatuner, and a gain of 10 dBd in the antenna.The Effective Radiated Power (ERP) is:"},{"questionId":"A-007-006-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2"},{"letter":"B","text":"4"},{"letter":"C","text":"6"},{"letter":"D","text":"1.5"}],"questionText":"If a 3 dBd gain antenna is replaced with a 9dBd gain antenna, with no other changes,the Effective Radiated Power (ERP) willincrease by:"},{"questionId":"A-007-006-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"9000"},{"letter":"B","text":"8000"},{"letter":"C","text":"1009"},{"letter":"D","text":"10 000"}],"questionText":"A transmitter has an output of 1000 wattsPEP. The coaxial cable, connectors andantenna tuner have a composite loss of 1dB, and the antenna gain is 10 dBd. What isthe Effective Radiated Power (ERP) in wattsPEP?"},{"questionId":"A-007-007-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It increases with increasing height"},{"letter":"B","text":"It does not vary with height"},{"letter":"C","text":"It depends on E-region height, notantenna height"},{"letter":"D","text":"It decreases with increasing height"}],"questionText":"For a 3-element Yagi antenna withhorizontally mounted elements, how doesthe main lobe takeoff angle vary with heightabove flat ground?"},{"questionId":"A-007-007-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"three-eighths of a wavelength above theground"},{"letter":"B","text":"a half wavelength or more above theground"},{"letter":"C","text":"an eighth of a wavelength above theground"},{"letter":"D","text":"a quarter wavelength above the ground"}],"questionText":"Most simple horizontally polarized antennasdo not exhibit significant directivity unlessthey are:"},{"questionId":"A-007-007-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"as much as a meter above ground"},{"letter":"B","text":"at ground level exactly"},{"letter":"C","text":"several centimeters to as much as 2meters below ground, depending uponsoil conditions"},{"letter":"D","text":"as much as 6 cm below grounddepending upon soil conditions"}],"questionText":"The plane from which ground reflections canbe considered to take place, or the effectiveground plane for an antenna is:"},{"questionId":"A-007-007-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It has an omnidirectional characteristic"},{"letter":"B","text":"It uses vertical polarization"},{"letter":"C","text":"The vertical radiation angle is lower"},{"letter":"D","text":"The radiation resistance is lower"}],"questionText":"Why is a ground-mounted vertical quarter-wave antenna in reasonably opensurroundings better for long distancecontacts than a half-wave dipole at a quarterwavelength above ground?"},{"questionId":"A-007-007-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"radiation pattern changes to produce sidelobes at 15 and 50 degrees"},{"letter":"B","text":"side lobe radiation is cancelled"},{"letter":"C","text":"radiation pattern is unaffected"},{"letter":"D","text":"vertical or upward radiation is effectivelycancelled"}],"questionText":"When a half-wave dipole antenna is installedone-half wavelength above ground, the:"},{"questionId":"A-007-007-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"If the antenna is less than one-halfwavelength high, reflected radio wavesfrom the ground significantly distort thepattern"},{"letter":"B","text":"Antenna height has no effect on thepattern"},{"letter":"C","text":"If the antenna is less than one-halfwavelength high, radiation off the ends ofthe wire is eliminated"},{"letter":"D","text":"If the antenna is too high, the patternbecomes unpredictable"}],"questionText":"How does antenna height affect thehorizontal (azimuthal) radiation pattern of ahorizontal dipole HF antenna?"},{"questionId":"A-007-007-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"length of the antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"vertical radiation angle of the antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"power applied to the antenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"main height of the antenna"}],"questionText":"Greater distance can be covered withmultiple-hop transmissions by decreasingthe:"},{"questionId":"A-007-007-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"600 ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"75 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"25 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"300 ohms"}],"questionText":"The impedance at the centre of a dipoleantenna more than 3 wavelengths aboveground would be nearest to:"},{"questionId":"A-007-007-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Low radiation angle for closer distances"},{"letter":"B","text":"The radiation resistance is higher"},{"letter":"C","text":"The ground tends to act as a reflector"},{"letter":"D","text":"Lower antenna noise temperature"}],"questionText":"Why can a horizontal antenna closer toground be advantageous for close rangecommunications on lower HF bands?"},{"questionId":"A-007-007-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A vertical antenna and a frequency belowthe maximum usable frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"A vertical antenna and a frequency abovethe lowest usable frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"A horizontal antenna less than 1/4wavelength above ground and a frequencybelow the current critical frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"A horizontal antenna at a height of half awavelength and an operating frequency atthe optimum working frequency"}],"questionText":"Which antenna system and operatingfrequency are most suitable for Near VerticalIncidence (NVIS) communications?"},{"questionId":"A-007-008-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The resistance in the atmosphere that anantenna must overcome to be able toradiate a signal"},{"letter":"B","text":"The specific impedance of an antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"The combined losses of the antennaelements and transmission line"},{"letter":"D","text":"The equivalent resistance that woulddissipate the same amount of power asthat radiated from an antenna"}],"questionText":"What is meant by the radiation resistance ofan antenna?"},{"questionId":"A-007-008-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To measure the near-field radiationdensity from a transmitting antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"To calculate the front-to-side ratio of theantenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"To calculate the front-to-back ratio of theantenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"To match impedances for maximumpower transfer"}],"questionText":"Why would one need to know the radiationresistance of an antenna?"},{"questionId":"A-007-008-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Transmission line length and antennaheight"},{"letter":"B","text":"Sunspot activity and time of day"},{"letter":"C","text":"It is a physical constant and is the samefor all antennas"},{"letter":"D","text":"Antenna location with respect to nearbyobjects and the conductorslength/diameter ratio"}],"questionText":"What factors determine the radiationresistance of an antenna?"},{"questionId":"A-007-008-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Radiation resistance plus transmissionresistance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Transmission line resistance plusradiation resistance"},{"letter":"C","text":"Radiation resistance plus spaceimpedance"},{"letter":"D","text":"Radiation resistance plus ohmicresistance"}],"questionText":"What is included in the total resistance of anantenna system?"},{"questionId":"A-007-008-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Measure the ratio of the signal strengthsof the radiated power lobes from the frontand rear of the antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"Note the two points where the signalstrength is down 3 dB from the maximumsignal point and compute the angulardifference"},{"letter":"C","text":"Draw two imaginary lines through theends of the elements and measure theangle between the lines"},{"letter":"D","text":"Measure the ratio of the signal strengthsof the radiated power lobes from the frontand side of the antenna"}],"questionText":"How can the approximate beamwidth of abeam antenna be determined?"},{"questionId":"A-007-008-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"(effective radiated power / transmitteroutput) x 100"},{"letter":"B","text":"(radiation resistance / total resistance) x100"},{"letter":"C","text":"(radiation resistance / transmissionresistance) x 100"},{"letter":"D","text":"(total resistance / radiation resistance) x100"}],"questionText":"How is antenna percent efficiencycalculated?"},{"questionId":"A-007-008-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Antenna resistance"},{"letter":"B","text":"K factor"},{"letter":"C","text":"Radiation resistance"},{"letter":"D","text":"j factor"}],"questionText":"What is the term used for an equivalentresistance which would dissipate the sameamount of energy as that radiated from anantenna?"},{"questionId":"A-007-008-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the 3 dB power points on the first minorlobe"},{"letter":"B","text":"the points on the major lobe at the half-power points"},{"letter":"C","text":"the maximum lobe spread points on themajor lobe"},{"letter":"D","text":"the 6 dB power points on the major lobe"}],"questionText":"Antenna beamwidth is the angular distancebetween:"},{"questionId":"A-007-008-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"100%"},{"letter":"B","text":"97.3%"},{"letter":"C","text":"74%"},{"letter":"D","text":"72%"}],"questionText":"If the ohmic resistance of a half-wave dipoleis 2 ohms, and the radiation resistance is 72ohms, what is the antenna efficiency?"},{"questionId":"A-007-008-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"25%"},{"letter":"B","text":"50%"},{"letter":"C","text":"96.15%"},{"letter":"D","text":"52%"}],"questionText":"If the ohmic resistance of a miniloop antennais 2 milliohms and the radiation resistance is50 milliohms, what is the antennaefficiency?"},{"questionId":"A-007-009-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"at frequencies above 3000 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"at frequencies above 2 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"at frequencies below 150 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"at frequencies below 1500 MHz"}],"questionText":"Waveguide is typically used:"},{"questionId":"A-007-009-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Frequency sensitive based ondimensions"},{"letter":"B","text":"Expensive"},{"letter":"C","text":"Heavy and difficult to install"},{"letter":"D","text":"Low loss"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is an advantage ofwaveguide as a transmission line?"},{"questionId":"A-007-009-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"one-eighth wavelength"},{"letter":"B","text":"one-quarter wavelength"},{"letter":"C","text":"one-half wavelength"},{"letter":"D","text":"three-eighths wavelength"}],"questionText":"For rectangular waveguide to transferenergy, the cross-section should be at least:"},{"questionId":"A-007-009-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"In the transverse magnetic mode, acomponent of the electric field is in thedirection of propagation"},{"letter":"B","text":"Waveguide has low loss at highfrequencies, but high loss below cutofffrequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"Waveguide has high loss at highfrequencies, but low loss below cutofffrequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"In the transverse electric mode, acomponent of the magnetic field is in thedirection of propagation"}],"questionText":"Which of the following statements aboutwaveguide IS NOT correct?"},{"questionId":"A-007-009-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Easy to install"},{"letter":"B","text":"Inexpensive to install"},{"letter":"C","text":"Very low losses"},{"letter":"D","text":"Frequency response from 1.8 MHz to24GHz"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is a major advantageof waveguide over coaxial cable for use atmicrowave frequencies?"},{"questionId":"A-007-009-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Dielectric substrate"},{"letter":"B","text":"Dielectric imprinting"},{"letter":"C","text":"Ground plane"},{"letter":"D","text":"Microstripline"}],"questionText":"What is printed circuit transmission linecalled?"},{"questionId":"A-007-009-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"must have much lower characteristicimpedance"},{"letter":"B","text":"must have much higher characteristicimpedance"},{"letter":"C","text":"has poorer shielding"},{"letter":"D","text":"has superior shielding"}],"questionText":"Compared with coaxial cable, microstripline:"},{"questionId":"A-007-009-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"is lightweight and easy to install"},{"letter":"B","text":"operates like a high-pass filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"operates like a low-pass filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"operates like a band-stop filter"}],"questionText":"A section of waveguide:"},{"questionId":"A-007-009-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"printed circuit transmission line"},{"letter":"B","text":"small semiconductor family"},{"letter":"C","text":"high power microwave antenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"family of fluids for removing coatings fromsmall parts"}],"questionText":"Stripline is a:"}]
